翻译：艾瑞卡  斑驳  消失的牛奶器
翻译：持久  德尼  二川
翻译：蓑笠翁  小英的小号  小蛮腰
校对：脸盆王子  吃货丁小七  somehacker
总监：somehacker
后期：aaaBαo
一想起我的妻子
When I think of my wife,
我就会想到她的头颅
I always think of her head.
幻想着砸开她可爱的小脑瓜
I picture cracking her lovely skull.
好好看看她的大脑
Unspooling her brains.
想找出答案
Trying to get answers.
婚姻里最重要的问题
The primal questions of any marriage.
"你在想什么"
"What are you thinking?"
"你感觉如何"
"How are you feeling?"
"我们都对彼此做了些什么"
"What have we done to each other?"
消失的爱人
七月五日
清
晨
那间酒吧
营业
爱尔兰王子大驾光临
The Irish prince graces us with his presence.
王子陛下不想被喷湿
His majesty prefers not to be moistened.
我给你买了份礼物
I got you a present.
-我讨厌这个游戏  -你喜欢的
- I hated this game. - You loved it.
优秀策划者
喜欢的是你
You loved it.
谢谢  架子上又多了一个游戏
Thank you. I'll add it to the collection.
能帮我倒杯波本吗
Can you pour me a bourbon?
怎么这么焦虑
What's up, jitters?
要是你不打算说
Well, if you're not going to talk,
那我就得再讲个闷死人的
I'm gonna have to fill the silence
马戈·邓恩的故事来打破沉寂了
with another excruciating story by Margo Dunne.
我可以跟你讲讲我最近遇上的客人
I could tell you about my recent customer service experience.
-不讲网络供应商了  -我爱听那个
- Changing Internet service providers. - I like that one.
或者上次我看到一个女人
Or how about the time I saw that woman
长得跟我朋友莫妮卡一模一样
who looked exactly like my friend Monica?
可她不是莫妮卡  完全不认识她
But it wasn't Monica. It was a total stranger.
刚好她也叫莫妮卡是吗
Who was also named Monica.
-听起来有点意思  -挺不错的
- Made it kind of interesting. - It's great.
我今天过得不好
I'm just having a bad day.
-艾米吗  -是结婚纪念日
- Amy? - It's our anniversary.
-五周年  -五年了
- Five years. - Five?
时光飞逝啊
That came fast.
还来势汹汹
And furious.
我现在简直开心疯了
I'm so crazy, stupid happy.
2005年1月8日
我遇见了一个男人
I met a boy.
一个贴心  帅气  又酷毙的好男人
A great, sweet, gorgeous, cool-ass guy.
打扰一下  小姐
Excuse me, miss?
我只想提醒你一下
I just want you to be careful
你的比利时私酿纯麦啤酒不要乱放
where you put down that monk-brewed Belgian wheat beer,
因为现在这派对上
because the party's down to
只剩下三箱破啤酒  和这瓶好酒
three beast lights and a bottle of pucker.
没准有人会来抢呢
It might attract some desperate characters.
或许吧  那些阿米什人刚成人  疯着呢
It could. I mean, the Amish are on a rumspringa.
我的冷肉拼盘吃不下去了  他们就抢走了
They already relieved me of my artisanal meat platter.
终于有人告诉我该怎么说那个词了
Finally, someone tells me how to pronounce that word.
"肉"吗
"Meat"?
对  就是"肉" 单音节
Yes, "Meat." One syllable.
谢谢  我这喝的是谁的酒
Thank you. Whose beer am I about to drink?
别告诉我
Don't tell me.
来看看谁是你喜欢的类型
Let's see, who's your type?
我没见你安静地坐下听那个人
I don't see you sitting quietly
马塞尔·普鲁斯特  19世纪末期法国文学家
长篇大论地讲他关于普鲁斯特的研究生论文
while he bloviates on his postgrad thesis about Proust.
是他吗
Is that him?
讽刺型嬉皮士  自我意识旺盛
Ironic hipster, so self-aware,
视一切为笑话
he makes everything a joke.
我喜欢幽默的人  不是滑稽
I prefer men who are funny, not "Funny."
那你是什么型的
What type are you?
土生土长的密苏里人
Corn-fed, salt-of-the-earth Missouri guy.
密苏里吗
Missouri?
挺可爱的
Cute.
纽约本地人
Native New Yorker?
哈德森河口就是世界尽头
The world ends at the Hudson.
你叫什么
What's your name?
艾米
Amy.
艾米  你是谁
Well, Amy, who are you?
A  我是一流的手工艺品家
A, I'm an award-winning scrimshander.
B  我是个有点影响力的小军阀
B, I'm a moderately influential warlord.
C  我给杂志写人格小测试
C, I write personality quizzes for magazines.
你这芊芊玉手肯定不是做工艺品的
Okay. Your hands are far too delicate for real scrimshaw work.
我刚好订阅了
And I happen to be a charter
小军阀周刊
subscriber to Middling Warlord Weekly.
你要真是我肯定认得出你
So I'd recognize you.
我选C
I'm gonna go with "C."
那你呢
And you?
你是谁
Who are you?
我是来把你拯救出来的人
I'm the guy to save you from all this awesomeness.
你给男性杂志写专栏
So, you write for a men's magazine.
老天  那你不就是男人界的专家
God, does that make you an expert on being a man?
不是  就是讲讲该穿什么  该喝什么
No. It's, you know, what to wear, what to drink.
还有该怎么胡扯
How to bullshit.
永远不会对你胡扯
Never with you.
得了吧
Ha, ha.
不  我说真的
No, I mean it.
很难相信你
It's hard to believe you.
为什么
Why?
可能是你下巴的缘故
I think it's your chin.
我的下巴
My chin?
是啊  看起来像个坏人
Yeah, it's quite villainous.
那这样呢
Okay, how's this?
百分百真诚  绝不胡扯
A hundred percent true, no bullshit.
好吧
Okay.
我们都搬到纽约
We all move to New York,
然后就住在这些
and we end up living in
小到不能再小的小房间里  但还没完
these little cubby holes, and that's not it.
一出门  你就身在其中了
Come outside. Then, you're in it.
你一定得看看这个
You have to see this.
你好
Hey.
我现在必须吻你了
I have to kiss you now.
是吗
Is that right?
你从头甜到了脚  怎么能不吻你
I can't let you go through a sugar storm unkissed.
等一下
Wait a second.
好了
There you go.
尼克·邓恩
Nick Dunne.
我真的很喜欢你
I really like you.
艾米是要弄个寻宝游戏
So, is Amy gonna do one of those anniversary,
纪念周年吗
treasure hunts?
你是说强行设计这么个游戏
You mean the forced march designed to prove
来证明她丈夫是个多失职不贴心的混蛋吗
what an oblivious and uncaring asshole her husband is?
"游戏人生"  我却不得要领
Life. I don't remember the point.
玩游戏玩出挺深刻的想法啊
Deep Hasbro thoughts.
该你了
Spin.
去年把她气疯了的那条线索是什么来着
What was the clue last year she got so mad about?
"当你可怜的艾米得了感冒
"When your poor Amy has a cold,
这个甜点就一定得卖掉"
this dessert just must be sold."
答案是什么
The answer?
我还是不知道
I still don't know the answer, go.
几年前你肯定知道
A few years ago, you'd have known.
几年前这游戏还很有意思
A few years ago, it was fun.
第一年  纸婚纪念
Year one, the traditional gift was paper.
她送了我一个特别漂亮的笔记本
She got me a beautiful notebook.
要我去写小说
Told me to go write my novel.
你给她送了什么
What did you get her?
风筝
A kite.
-她从来不放风筝  -好吧
- She'd never flown a kite. - Okay.
那说第四年  花婚
Anyway. Year four, flowers.
她引着我去后院的枯萎玫瑰花丛
She led me outside to the dying rosebush in the backyard.
挺有象征意义
That's symbolic.
没错
Yeah.
第五年呢
What's the gift for five?
木婚
Wood.
-你送她什么  -木头做不出好礼物
- So, what did you get her? - There's no good gift for wood.
我知道  回家
I know! Go home,
操到她神志不清  再用你的大屌扇她
fuck her brains out, slap her with your penis.
"这是你要的木头[阴茎]  婊子"
"There's some wood for you, bitch."
那间酒吧
The Bar.
怎么  是的  等一下
Why, yes. Hang on one second.
是沃利这个监控狂
Hey, it's watchful Wally.
你好  沃特  怎么了
Hey, Walt. What's going on?
非常谢谢  马上到  好的  再见
Thanks very much. I'll be right there. All right, bye-bye.
小家伙  你在外面干什么
Hey, buddy. What are you doing out here?
谢谢  沃特
Thanks, Walt!
艾米
Ame?
Amy!
有人吗
Hello?
进来
Come on in.
你好
Hey.
-邓恩先生  -你好
- Mister Dunne. - Hi.
我是朗达·邦妮警探  这位是詹姆斯·吉尔平警官
I'm detective Rhonda Boney. This is officer James Gilpin.
我知道你现在很担心你妻子
We understand there are concerns about your wife.
我不知道我妻子在哪  一回来就看到这个
I don't know where my wife is. And I came home to this.
我一般不会恐慌
Now, I don't panic easily,
但这也太诡异了
but it's weird, right?
介意我们四处看看吗
Mind if we look around?
请便
Please.
你们住这多久了
How long have you two been here?
到九月就两年了  我们之前住在纽约
Two years in September. We used to live in New York.
纽约市吗
City?
没错  我是个作家  我俩都写作
Yeah, I was a writer. We were both writers.
你们为什么搬回来
Why did you all move back here?
我妈妈生病了
My mom got sick.
很抱歉  她还好吗
Oh, I'm sorry. How is she?
她过世了
She's dead.
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
那你现在做什么工作
What do you do now, for work?
我和我姐姐在市中心开了那间酒吧
My sister Margo and I own the Bar downtown.
那间酒吧啊
Oh, the bar.
名字大爱  挺有创意的
Love the name. Very meta.
谢谢
Thanks.
挺漂亮的
Pretty things.
待在这
Stay.
那是我办公室
My office, here.
裙子真漂亮
Beautiful dress.
约会夜吗
Date night?
是结婚纪念日
It's our anniversary.
这里是客房
It's a guest bedroom, there.
尽头是猫的房间
Cat's room on the end.
我上来查过了
I checked up here.
这就是厨房了吧
This is the kitchen obviously.
这里是...
This is the...
这是我妻子的办公室
This is my wife's office.
艾米的办公室
Amy's office.
挺厉害的姑娘
Wow. Impressive gal.
哈佛大学文学学士
耶鲁大学心理学讲师
我该担心吗
Yeah. Should I be concerned?
我记得这个
I remember these.
我最喜欢这些书
I loved these books.
等等
Wait a minute.
你妻子就是了不起的艾米吗
Your wife is the amazing Amy?
没错  正是
Yeah. She is.
他妈的了不起的艾米要他妈的结婚了
Amazing-fucking-Amy is getting fucking married.
2007年2月24日
那晚是这样开始的
That's how the night started.
我  普通的  不完美的  真实的艾米
With me, regular, flawed, real Amy,
一如既往地嫉妒着全能天才
jealous, as always, of the golden child,
要是值得去做  那就值得做得漂亮
完美的  聪明的  了不起的艾米
perfect, brilliant, amazing Amy,
竟然他妈的要结婚了
who's getting fucking married.
我十岁时放弃学大提琴
When I was 10, I quit cello.
下本书里了不起的艾米就成了大提琴天才
In the next book, amazing Amy became a prodigy.
你打排球吗
Did you play volleyball?
我大一就被刷下来了
I got cut, freshman year.
她进了大学校队
She made varsity.
你什么时候养狗了
When did you have a dog?
是她养的
She got the dog.
"小邋遢"让她更贴近生活
Puddles made her more relatable.
我爱你父母
I love your parents,
但他们有时候真的挺混蛋的
but they really can be assholes.
-尼克  -先生
- Nick! - Sir!
感谢你能来
Hey, thanks for coming, man.
不成问题
No problem.
你好  亲爱的
Hey, sweetheart.
今晚对你妈妈很重要
Big night for your mom.
你去跟几个记者还有博主说两句
It would mean so much if you would talk to a few reporters, bloggers,
给他们点小艾米的料
give them a little Amy color.
大家想听你亲述
People wanna hear from you.
-我们待不了多久  -好极了
- We can't stay long. - Fantastic.
最多十五分钟
Fifteen minutes, tops.
我能进入这个圈子  能有信托基金多亏了他们
This is why I have my brownstone, my trust fund.
我知道我不能抱怨
I know I can't complain.
你父母完全就是剽窃了你的童年
Your parents literally plagiarized your childhood.
不  他们升华了它  然后兜售给读者
No, they improved upon it, and then peddled it to the masses.
我以为你会穿白衣服来贴合婚礼主题
I thought you were gonna wear white to match the wedding theme.
我觉得会很怪
I thought that would be creepy.
"要是值得去做  那就值得..."
"If it's worth doing, it's worth doing..."
等等  我知道最后怎么说的  别告诉我
Hold up! I know how this ends. Don't tell me.
你真可爱  尼克
You're very cute, Nick.
艾米  你知道该怎么让你爸爸开心
Amy, you know what would make dad's night.
马上去
I'm on it.
我最喜欢陌生人来揭我伤疤
I love having strangers pick at my scabs.
我很好奇
I'm curious whether
你看到了不起的艾米走上红毯会不会难过
it's difficult for you to see amazing Amy heading down the aisle.
还有这个庆祝这场虚拟婚礼的盛大派对
And this big party celebrating this fictional wedding.
因为据我所知  你还未婚
Because it's my understanding you are not married.
是真的吗
Is that correct?
没错  了不起的艾米总是先我一步
Correct. Amazing Amy has always been one step ahead of me.
抱歉  对不起  我有几个问题
Excuse me. I'm sorry, I just have a few questions.
是你啊
It's you.
我是秉着严谨的新闻态度来问的
I'm here in a strictly journalistic capacity.
现在你跟尼克·邓恩
Now, you had the distinct pleasure
愉快地交往了多久了
of dating Nick Dunne for how long?
-美妙的两年  -美妙的两年啊
- Two magical years. - Two magical years.
在这段时间里  你非常体贴
In the course of that time, you've had the opportunity
比如尼克把"藜麦"说成"梨买"
to perform such gracious gestures as
你也不去纠正他
not correcting Nick when he pronounced "Quinoa" as "Kween-o-a."
可以理解的错误
An understandable mistake.
他以为藜麦是种鱼
He also thought it was a fish.
他还以为美式软奶酪是奶酪
He thinks Velveeta is a cheese.
尼克年迈的母亲每次见到你
You also manage to appear shocked and delighted
电影《纽约纽约》主题曲  后成为纽约市代表曲  许多纽约的社交场合都可听到
都会即兴表演《纽约纽约》时
when Nick's elderly mother breaks into an impromptu rendition
你每次都能表现得很惊喜
Of New York, New York, every time she sees you.
这些破鞋子
These vegabond shoes.
别吓人了
That's just frightening.
你还给尼克买了他人生中第一把剪刀
You also bought Nick his very first pair of scissors.
还有配套的订书机
And matching stapler.
艾米 艾略特  你不单是了不起
Amy Elliott, you are more than amazing.
你才华横溢还不矫揉造作
You are brilliant, yet entirely un-snobby.
你让我充满挑战  充满惊喜
You challenge me. You surprise me.
还有给读者爆点料
And, fun fact for the readers,
你床上功夫世界一流
you have a world-class vagina.
我的同僚们告诉我你还未婚
My colleagues tell me that you are not yet married.
是否正确
Is that correct?
我是未婚
I'm not.
我们是不是该解决下这个问题了
Isn't it time we fixed that?
然后
And then...
那晚便不再糟糕了
the night wasn't so bad anymore.
好了  这事算完成了
And it's done. Crossed off the list.
这种案子我们一般来说
Now, normally, we would not
不会马上以失踪案处理
treat this as a missing persons case so quick,
但鉴于你屋子里的情况
but given the scene at your house,
还有最近激增的暴力犯罪事件
and given our spike in violent crime of late,
我们会严肃处理这起案件
We are gonna take this very, very seriously.
好的  很好
Okay. Good.
我们派了鉴定科的人去你家
We've got forensics over at your place.
你有别的地方住吗
You got somewhere to stay?
-我可以住我姐姐那  -好
- I could stay at my sister's. - Okay.
我们会追踪艾米的手机  信用卡
We're tracking Amy's phone, her credit cards.
还会组织搜索  张贴传单
We will organize searches, put up flyers.
明天就开新闻发布会
We're gonna hold a press conference tomorrow.
你们要开新闻发布会吗
You're having a press conference?
引起大家重视
I wanna get the word out, right?
是啊  只是突然感觉
Yeah, it's just all of a sudden,
美国电视史上播映时间最长犯罪剧集
自己好像在演《法律与秩序》
I feel like I'm on a Law & Order episode.
此类案件时间都很紧迫
Now, time is of the essence in these cases.
但话说回来  你想找律师吗
But, that said, do you wanna wait and call a lawyer?
完全不用  我想帮忙
Absolutely not. I just wanna help.
你和艾米来这两年了
So, you and Amy have been here two years.
-你是酒保  -我是老板
- You tend bar... - I own the bar.
我还在莫霍克谷社区学院教创意写作
And I teach creative writing at mvcc.
-没有孩子  -还没有
- No kids? - Not yet.
那艾米通常都做什么
So, what does Amy do most days?
有那么多学位  她都做些什么
A woman with all those degrees, what does she do?
我也不知道  她一直都挺忙的
I don't know. She keeps busy.
忙什么
Doing what?
其实  她特别爱读书
Yeah, I mean, She's a voracious reader.
所以她手里随时都拿着一本书
So, she's always got a book in her hand.
不过  长日漫漫
Well, days can get long.
我认识几个家庭主妇
I know a few housewives,
中午就开始喝红酒了
that evening glass of wine starts coming at noon.
有的是吃处方药
Or prescription pills.
就在上周  有一位足球妈妈
Just last week, we had a soccer mom.
全职顾家支持孩子学习生活的母亲
人很好
Nice lady.
因为吃奥施康定[止痛药]出事掉了几颗牙
Got her teeth kicked in over some oxycontin.
自从那间商场倒闭  半个城的人都失业了
Ever since that mall went bust, half the town is out of work.
毒品暴力的问题我们实在处理不过来
We cannot keep up with the drug violence.
我保证  不是毒品暴力的问题
I'm pretty sure that's not it.
艾米有没有什么朋友可以跟我们谈一谈
Has Amy got friends we can talk to?
没  没有
No, not really.
这么大的地方  连一个朋友都没有
No friends? This whole town?
我妈去世以前  她和我妈的关系很好
She was very close with my mom, before she passed away.
我们小区那一带的流浪汉
You know, we have a pretty serious homeless problem.
很是问题的
In our neighborhood.
我觉得你们应该查查这个
I think maybe you guys should check that out.
我们会调查的
We'll look into that.
你今天十一点左右到酒吧
So, you got to the bar around 11:00 today.
那之前你在哪儿  正常排查而已
Where were you before that? Just to cross that out.
早上我在家
Well, I was home.
九点半出门  买了杯咖啡跟报纸
I left at 9:30, I got a cup of coffee, a newspaper.
到索耶海滩看了会儿报纸
I went to Sawyer beach and read the news.
你在那有碰见谁吗
Did you visit with anyone there?
我就图那里没人打扰
I kind of go to Sawyer beach for the solitude.
所以说  你妻子在这里没有朋友
So, your wife has no friends here.
那她是不是比较冷漠呢
Is she kinda standoffish?
读了名校  心高气傲什么的
Ivy league? Rubs people the wrong way?
她是纽约来的
She's from New York.
她比较复杂  生活标准很高
She's complicated. She's got very high standards.
A型人格
Type A?
如果性格不合  A型性格的人能把你逼疯
That can make you crazy if you're not like that.
你看起来比较闲散  是B型人格
You seem pretty laid-back. Type B.
顺便问一下  艾米是什么血型
Speaking of which, Amy's blood type?
老天  我不知道  我得回家查一下
God, I don't know. I'd have to look it up at the house.
你不知道她有没有朋友
You don't know if she has friends,
也不知道她每天都做些什么
you don't know what she does all day.
连你老婆的血型都不知道
And you don't know your wife's blood type.
你确定你俩结婚了吗
Sure you all are married?
可能是O型
Maybe it's type O.
-她的父母在哪  纽约吗  -是的
- Where are her folks? New York? - Yeah.
他们能及时赶过来参加明天的新闻发布会吗
Can they get here in time for this press conference tomorrow?
明天吗  我不知道  我还没告诉他们
Tomorrow? I have no idea. I haven't talked to them.
你还没给你老婆的父母打电话
You haven't called your wife's parents yet?
这栋楼又没信号
You can't get a signal in this building.
你又一直在跟我谈话
I've been in here talking to you.
给他们打电话  尼克  现在就打
Call them, please, Nick. Now.
好吧
Fine.
我应该知道自己老婆的血型吗
Should I know my wife's blood type?
不用
No.
抱歉  玛丽贝思  我也不知道是怎么回事
I apologize, Marybeth. I didn't know what was going on.
我现在在警局
You know, now I'm at the station.
家里都是警察
And the cops are at the house,
事情比较严重  所以我给你打电话
and it's serious and I'm calling you.
现在很多事情都还不清楚
There's a lot of things that are being juggled right now.
我现在就站在朗达·邦妮警探旁边
I'm standing right next to detective Rhonda Boney.
她负责这个案件
Who's the lead investigator on this and she's...
我岳母想跟你说几句
My mother-in-law would like to speak with you.
我是邦妮警探
This is detective Boney.
我想回家
I wanna go home.
我不明白为什么我得待在这
I don't know why I have to be here.
我不想在这  我想回家
I don't wanna be here. I wanna go home.
爸爸
Dad?
这是我父亲  出什么事了
This is my father. What's going on?
是吗  你就是尼克·邓恩
Really? You're Nick Dunne?
联系你一下午都没找到你
We've been trying to get a hold of you all afternoon.
我就在那儿  我老婆失踪了
I've been right there. My wife is missing.
-贱货  -别说了
- Bitch. - Don't.
你父亲午饭后离开养老院四处游荡
Your father wandered out of comfort hill after lunch.
我们在79号公路发现了他  他迷路了
We found him walking route 79, disoriented.
我们一直在给你打电话  跟你联系...
We've been trying to call you for the last...
我手机在这栋楼里收不到信号
I don't get a cell signal in this building.
我就坐在离你二十英尺的地方
I've been sitting 20 feet away from you.
先生  请不要用这种语气跟我说话
Sir, please don't take that tone with me.
又笨又蠢又丑的贱货
Stupid, dumb, ugly bitch.
爸爸  别说了
Dad, stop.
你要不要先送他回去
You wanna drive him home?
最好是这样  谢谢
I think that would be wise. Thanks.
语音信箱已满
This voice mailbox is currently full.
操
Fuck.
养老院
把你的脏手拿开
Get your fucking hands off me.
谢谢
Thanks.
2009年7月5日
每个人都一而再地告诫我们
Everyone told us and told us and told us.
维持婚姻很辛苦
Marriage is hard work.
需要相互妥协  还要努力经营
And compromise and more work.
"进入炼狱之人  勿抱尘世之望"[《神曲》]
"Abandon all hope, ye who enter."
"当小艾米的希望日趋减退
"When young Amy's hope did wane.
"她流连于此
"She wandered here."
但并非如此  对我和尼克来说不是这样
Well, it's not true. Not for me and Nick.
"寻找简·奥斯汀
"In search of Jane."
两年之于我们而言
With us, two years,
正是浓情蜜意时
it's just good.
奥斯汀
Austen.
你是个独来独往的姑娘
You were an alienated teen,
只有伊丽莎白·班内特能懂你
and only Elizabeth Bennet understood you.
《傲慢与偏见》女主角
看看
Look at that.
老天爷
My God.
你这个风骚的女子
You naughty minx.
通常我们进入下一步才能做爱
Well, technically, we are supposed to fuck at the next stop.
没错  比较合传统
Yeah, in keeping with tradition.
但我觉得这次可以通融一下
But I might be willing to bend the rules this once.
求老天保佑简·奥斯汀
God bless Jane Austen.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我可是热情洋溢的  看看  有此为证
I'm enthusiastic. Look at that. It's confirmed by the...
谢谢
Thank you.
两周年纪念日  棉婚
Year two. Cotton.
之前不是开玩笑说
It's, we had that joke that
我们的性生活好到普通床单无法承受
our sex was too good for ordinary.
这床单有两千支...
So, these are 2,000 thread-count...
太可爱了  真想往咱俩脸上揍一拳
We're so cute. I wanna punch us in the face.
太好了  真的  太棒了
That's pretty great. I mean, that is pretty great.
他们有没有问你需不需要请律师
Did they ask if you wanted a lawyer?
我不需要律师  好了  我来吧
I don't need a lawyer. Here, I'll do this.
那他们有没有问关于艾米的私人问题
Well, did they ask personal stuff about Amy?
他们问了
You know, they asked,
为什么她没朋友
why didn't she have any friends?
那你怎么回答的
What did you say?
-我说她比较复杂  -尼克
- I said she was complicated. - Nick!
所有人都知道  复杂的意思就是贱人
Everyone knows "Complicated" is code for "Bitch."
天哪  我觉得很难受
God. I feel sick.
谢谢
Thanks.
这也太奇怪了
It's so bizarre.
感觉这种事一定会发生在艾米身上似的
It seems like the kind of thing that would happen to Amy.
她总是那么...
She always attracts...
戏剧性
Drama?
你可以说的  就我们俩
You can say it. It's just me and you.
虽然我不喜欢和艾米待在一起
Just because I don't like to be around Amy,
但这不代表我不关心她
Doesn't mean I don't care about her.
无论如何  带她走的人肯定会带她回来的
Anyway, whoever took her is bound to bring her back.
警探  你好
Detective? Excuse me.
我是诺艾尔·霍桑  艾米最好的朋友
I'm Noelle Hawthorne. I'm Amy's best friend.
很好  那你家住哪里呢  诺艾尔
Well, great. Where do you live, Noelle?
隔着五户人家  1032号
Five doors down. 1032.
真好  能跟你谈谈真好
Wonderful. I would love to talk to you.
我半个小时以后来可以吗
Can I come by in half an hour?
-有什么消息了吗  -不好意思
- Y'all know anything yet? - I'm sorry.
我还有人在这工作  给我半小时
I got guys on the clock in here. But you give me 30 minutes.
但那个时间我一般都在洗澡
But that's usually bath time.
那就边洗边说
Well, we'll talk in between shampoos.
好了  有什么发现吗
All right. So, what do you got?
你在厨房看到的肯定是溅出来的血
It was definitely blood spatter you saw in the kitchen.
厨房嘛  刀具  准备食物什么的
Normally, kitchen, knives, food prep.
应该不奇怪  但那片血迹太高了
Not that weird, but that is awfully high.
所以我还要做一下荧光血迹测试
So, I'm gonna order a luminol sweep.
没问题
Well, okay.
有意思
Interesting.
怎么了
What's that?
房子是以她的名义租的  车也在她名下
House is rented in her name. Car's in her name.
信用卡  家用设施  电话账单
Credit cards, utilities, phone bill,
都是她的名字
all in her name.
连他的酒吧都是在她的名下
Even his bar's in her name.
我不明白这有什么好奇怪的
I don't know that that's so surprising.
不奇怪  但很耻辱
No. But it is humiliating.
有什么线索
What you got?
在她难以启齿的秘密里找到的
It's with her unmentionables.
我们的第一条线索
Well, we have our first clue.
七月六日
消失
一天后
我得去洗个澡
I have to take a shower.
不  别洗  你一晚都没睡
No, don't. You've been up all night.
你得看着像一夜没睡的样子
You wanna look like you've been up all night.
今天小心点  好吗
Hey, be careful today, okay?
说得还真奇怪
That's a weird thing to say.
你郁闷的时候就会喝酒
Well, when you're upset, you bottle up.
看起来比较愤怒  就像...
You can seem angry, like...
千万别说  跟老爸一副德行
please don't say, "Like dad."
要么你就得发动你的乖宝宝魅力攻势
Or else you swing into your momma's-boy charm offensive,
不过那就有点不正经了
and that can feel glib.
很好
Perfect.
我会尽量照顾你的玻璃心的
I'll balance on the exact fucking edge of your emotional razor.
好了  你只要
Okay. Just be...
做自己
Myself?
资助了一个彩票抽奖售票店以造福西部人民
Sponsoring a raffle to benefit west county 4h.
抽奖销售密苏里足球队的季度赛球票
And raffling season tickets for mizzou football.
你可以在烤翅店或轮胎店买到球票
Buy your tickets at the wing hut or local tri-state tire stores.
你的岳父岳母赶过来了
Your in-laws made it.
-兰德  -孩子
- Hi, Rand. - Hey, man.
我是邦妮警探
I'm detective Boney.
我是他的孪生姐姐  马尔
I'm the twin. Margo.
我们昨天打了网球  到现在还没缓过来
We played tennis yesterday, Nick. I just can't get over it.
玛丽贝思  真的很抱歉
Marybeth, I am really sorry.
我就知道  你们不应该搬回来
I knew you never should have moved back here.
我们也是没办法
We didn't have a lot of choice.
我们都很担心  很害怕
We are all worried. We are all scared.
但我们现在也都来了
But we are all here now.
我们一起努力  肯定能找到艾米的
And we will find Amy, together.
是不是我先来  然后你们再说点什么
Should I just go first, and then you guys can say something?
好的
Good.
大家都知道  我的妻子艾米·艾略特·邓恩
As you know, my wife, Amy Elliott Dunne.
七月五日在家中莫名失踪
Disappeared from our home on the morning of July 5th.
留下许多可疑的线索
Under suspicious circumstances.
声音大一点
Louder!
不管谁有了消息
If anyone out there has any information.
请站出来
Please come forward.
谢谢
Thank you.
我叫兰德·艾略特
I'm Rand Elliott.
这是我的妻子玛丽贝思·艾略特
My wife, Marybeth Elliott.
我应该说名字吗
Should I have said my name?
艾米是我们的独生女儿
Amy is our only child.
她阳光  美丽  善良
She's bright, she's beautiful. She's kind.
她确实是了不起的艾米
She really is amazing Amy.
有成百上千万的人
You know, there are millions of people out there,
陪伴她长大  关心她  爱护她
who grew up with her and care about her.
我们关心她  我们很爱她
We care about her, we love her.
我们只想让她回家
And we just want her back.
艾米是位颇有成就的学者
Amy is a decorated scholar.
在新闻界闯出了一片天
She forged a successful career in journalism.
之后她回到丈夫的家乡
She returned here to her husband's hometown,
在婆家开始了新的生活
and she made a life in her adopted home.
而现在  艾米需要你的帮助
Now, Amy needs your help.
我们在特鲁里旅馆设立了志愿者中心
We're establishing a volunteer headquarters at the Drury lodge.
热线电话是18854寻找艾米
We have a hotline, 1-855-4-Amy-tips.
我们的网址名称是"寻找了不起的艾米"
And our website is www.Findamazingamy.com.
-邓恩先生  -艾略特先生
- Mr. Dunne! - Mr. Elliott!
邓恩先生  有没有凶杀的迹象
Mr. Dunne, any signs of foul play?
艾略特先生  你上次跟女儿联系是什么时候
Mr. Elliott, when was the last time you spoke to your daughter?
笑一笑
Smile.
到此为止  谢谢大家
That's all for now. Thank you.
艾米有很多仰慕者
Amy is the kind of girl who attracts admirers.
对吧  尼克
Right, Nick?
是的  确实如此
Yeah, definitely.
我们有过活生生的例子
And we've had instances.
-这事有点...  -吓人
- Where things got... - scary.
你知道德西·柯林斯吗
Do you know about Desi Collings?
是的  德西·柯林斯的事我都知道
Yeah, I know all about Desi Collings.
他对艾米很着迷
He was obsessed.
高二那年艾米和他分手后还自杀过
He attempted suicide after Amy broke up with him sophomore year.
我们不得不申请了禁令
We had to file a restraining order.
这是高中的事了吧  二十年前
This would be high school? Twenty years ago?
但他最近搬到圣路易斯  离这只有两小时
But he recently moved to St. Louis. That's just two hours away.
不过  他家就是圣路易斯的
To be fair, he is from St. Louis.
还有汤米·欧哈拉
We also have Tommy O'Hara.
这个只是八年前  在纽约
This is only eight years ago, in New York.
他俩分手以后  他就变得很暴力
She broke up with him, he got very physical.
-她起诉了  -罪名是什么
- She filed charges. - What was the charge?
性侵  威胁  恐吓  殴打还是什么
Sexual assault, threat, battery, what?
我只知道情况很糟糕
I only know it was bad.
-这事我怎么不知道  -好吧
- I didn't know this. - Okay.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
还有最近的吗
Anything more recent?
据我所知没有了
Not that I know of.
尼克  有时间吗
Hey, Nick? You got a minute?
有
Yeah.
想想我们得多迷惑
Imagine our confusion.
在一起人口失踪案里
A missing persons case.
却在妻子的衣帽间
And in your wife's dressing room,
发现了一封写有"线索"两个字的信封
we find an envelope marked "Clue."
那是为我们的结婚纪念日准备的
That's for our anniversary.
我老婆喜欢寻宝游戏
My wife does these treasure hunts.
我希望你能告诉我们这是什么意思
I'm hoping you can tell me what this means.
你想玩艾米的寻宝游戏
You want to solve Amy's treasure hunt?
这有助于我们了解艾米失踪前的动向
It'll help me track Amy's movements before she disappeared.
当然  可以
Of course. Okay.
"尽管空间狭窄
"Although this spot couldn't be tighter,
"却是我最爱作家的温床
"It's a cozy room for my favorite writer."
这个我知道
I know this one!
尽管空间狭窄
Although this spot couldn't be any tighter,
却是我最爱作家的温床
It's a cozy room for my favorite writer.
下课铃响  就来见我
After-school meeting, don't mind if I do.
看我这个老师合不合格
Maybe I'll teach you a thing or two.
这个上面写了什么
Well, well. What does it say?
线索二
Clue two.
"帅哥  我们来玩间谍游戏吧
"Hey, handsome man, let's go undercover.
"你来演间谍  我来当情人
"You'll be the spy, and I'll be his lover.
"我们携手并肩
"Let's head on over.
"去往那间棕色小屋
"To the little brown house.
"一起扮演热辣亲密的夫妻  甜蜜相爱的伴侣
"We'll play hot, doting husband, sweet, loving spouse."
这是你的吗
These yours?
不是
No.
不过你也看过第一条线索
But you read the first clue.
好色的教授  淫荡的学生
Randy Professor, naughty student.
我脸都红了
I blush.
我和我前任只送过卡片
Me and my ex just swapped cards.
这个棕色小屋在哪儿
Where's this little brown house?
我不知道
I have no idea.
帮助找寻
艾米·邓恩
请拨18854
寻找艾米
你好
Hello?
我是尼古拉斯·邓恩
Nicholas Dunne.
这房子登记在我父亲威廉·邓恩名下
Under my father's name, William Dunne.
我妻子的第一只宠物  这有必要吗
My wife's first pet? Is this necessary?
能不能把警报...
Can you just turn the bell...
我知道
yeah, I know.
是"小邋遢"吗  还是"贵宾犬"
It's "Puddles", right? Or is it "Poodles"?
没事了
We're good.
你好啊  陌生人
Hello, stranger.
没想到能在这遇到你
Fancy meeting you here.
这是你爸爸的屋子吧
It's your dad's house, right?
你在跟踪我吗
Are you following me?
你来这干什么
What you doing?
如你所说  这是我爸的屋子
Like you said, it's my dad's house.
我每周都会来看一眼  防止失火什么的
I come by once a week, make sure the place hasn't burned down.
看来今天还好
But it looks okay.
我送你出去吧
I'll walk you out.
我觉得这就是所谓的棕色小屋了
You know, I thought maybe this was the little brown house.
线索里提到的那栋
From the clue.
不可能  明明是蓝色
Nope. Still blue.
想象我是个很坏很坏的女孩
Picture me, I'm a girl who's very, very bad.
我必须受到惩罚  活该被逮个正着
I need to be punished, and by "Punished," I mean "Had."
有人在那里为结婚五周年藏起了好东西
It's where you keep goodies for anniversary five.
"快打开门来  仔细瞧一瞧
"So open the door, and look alive."
贱货
Bitch!
2010年7月18日
想找到你婚姻的软肋吗
Want to test your marriage for weak spots?
只需加一场经济萧条
Add one recession.
再减去两份工作
Subtract two jobs.
出奇地有效
It's surprisingly effective.
答应我永远别像他们一样
Promise me we'll never be like them.
像谁一样
Like who?
那些失败的夫妻
All those awful couples we know.
妻子把丈夫当成马戏团的猴子
Those wives who treat their men like dancing monkeys.
训着管着还得带出去给人看
To be trained and paraded.
丈夫眼中妻子就跟公路巡警似的
Husbands who treat their wives like the highway patrol.
怕着躲着还得时刻算计着
To be out-foxed and avoided.
我快被炒鱿鱼了
I think I'm gonna be laid off.
虽然现在经济衰退
We're in a recession.
不过没有过不去的坎儿
If it happens, we'll deal with it.
我可能也会失业
I'll probably be next.
但我们拥有彼此
We have each other.
别的都是身外之物
Everything else is background noise.
你真是独一无二
You are exceptional.
到我说了
My turn.
我父母的出版商不理他们
My parents' publisher dropped them,
他们现在债台高筑
and they're in debt up to their ears.
真糟糕
That's terrible.
他们得从我的信托基金里拿钱还债
And they need to borrow from my trust fund.
花了多少
How much?
差不多一百万
Almost a million.
那不是要用完了吗
That's almost all of it.
所以轮到你说"别的都是身外之物"了
This is where you say, "Everything else is background noise."
艾米  要是你失业了
Amy, if you're laid off.
我也失业了
And I'm laid off.
我已经决定好了
I said I'd do it.
都不和我商量一下吗
Without talking to me?
-其实...  -你说了算
- Well, it's... - Your call.
这本来就是他们的钱
Their money, technically.
你说得对
You know what? You're right.
别的都是身外之物
Everything else is just background noise.
还买游戏
More games?
没错  满足一下开枪杀人的欲望
Yeah, I just wanted to shoot some folks.
那买这手提电脑干什么
What's the laptop for?
用
Laptoping.
我算明白了
I see.
你能在不和我商量的前提下
You can give your parents $879,000
借你父母八十八万还债
without talking to me,
而我未经你允许买款游戏就犯了天条了
but God forbid I buy a video game without getting your permission.
你买的太多了
You are spending a lot.
你不相信我  你不相信我的判断
You don't trust me. You don't trust my judgment.
甚至怀疑我的动机
You certainly don't trust my intention.
你在胡扯什么
What are you talking about?
这是咱俩婚前约法三章的
That's the basic tenet of a prenup, isn't it?
你怎么又拿这事来说理
Why are you throwing that in my face again?
因为我本来就占理
Because it's easy to throw.
尼克  我不明白
Nick, I don't get it.
为什么你要逼着我变成我不喜欢的样子
I don't get why you're daring me to be someone I don't wanna be.
变成一个唠唠叨叨控制欲爆表的泼妇
The nagging shrew. The controlling bitch.
我不是那样的人  我是你妻子
I'm not that person. I'm your wife.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我只是有点不知所措  我还未曾失业过
I just don't know how to do this. I've never not had a job.
以前我卖过汉堡  刷过墙  我不...
I flipped burgers, I painted houses. I don't...
你会找到新工作的
You'll get another job.
嗨  马尔
Hi, go.
什么  等等  你说什么
What? Hold on. What?
-突然间  -慢点儿说  怎么了
- And suddenly. - Slow down, what is it?
我发现一切只会变得更糟
I knew everything was about to get worse.
告诉我发生了什么事
Okay, tell me what's wrong.
七月七日
消失
两天后
-上帝保佑你  尼克  -神父
- Bless you, Nick. - Father.
汤姆  镇长先生  你们好
Hey, Tom. Mayor!
尼克  很高兴见到你
Nick, good to see you.
我也是
Good to see you.
小朋友们
Hey, guys, hey.
-乔蒂  -尼克
- Jodie. - Nick.
我们会找到她的
Oh, we'll find her.
你脸色真差
You look like hammered shit.
谢谢
Thank you.
你见过那个戴眼镜的家伙吗
You ever see that guy in the glasses before?
别担心  我们录下了
Don't worry. We videotape everybody
所有出入这栋建筑的人
that comes in and out of these things.
你似乎找了不少
I mean, you tend to get a lot of...
伪善人
Do-gooders?
怪人
Freaks.
我想问问你
Hey, I meant to ask you.
诺艾尔·霍桑
Noelle Hawthorne?
她是你邻居  也是艾米最好的朋友
She lives on your street. Amy's best friend.
从没听过诺艾尔·霍桑这名字
I've never heard the name Noelle Hawthorne.
就是有三胞胎的那一家
She and her husband have triplets.
可能打过几次招呼
Yeah, we might say hi to them on the street.
但绝不是什么最好的朋友
But "Best friend"? No.
抱歉  我过去一下
Excuse me, one sec.
他表现得就像和诺艾尔完全没有来往
He acted like Noelle was a complete stranger.
意料之中
Of course he did.
来  这两个给你
Look, these two are yours.
看  他又在演好人了
Oh, look. He's being a good guy,
这样所有人才会觉得他是无辜的
so everybody can see him being a good guy.
你还真是不喜欢他啊
You really don't like him, do you?
他哪儿讨人喜欢了
What's to like?
语音信箱已满  按1转到
This mailbox is currently full. Press one to...
尼克  请容我自我介绍一下  我叫肖纳·凯利
Nick? I just wanted to introduce myself. My name's Shawna Kelly.
我为你遇到的麻烦表示遗憾
I am so sorry for your troubles.
谢谢关心
Thank you. That's kind.
你最近有好好吃饭吗
Are you remembering to eat?
吃了不少冻肉
Well, a lot of cold cuts.
那你可得尝尝我闻名世界的玉米鸡肉派
I'm gonna fix you up my world-famous chicken frito pie.
十分感谢  不过不用劳烦了
That's very kind and very unnecessary.
吃饱才有力气做事
You have to keep your strength.
你能...
Would you...
说"玉米鸡肉派"
Say, "Chicken frito pie!"
能麻烦你删了这张照片吗
You know what? Would you delete that picture for me?
-拍的很棒呀  -我知道
- It's a nice photo. - I know it is.
就当帮我个忙
But just do me a favor.
行吗
Will you?
拜托你删了这张照片吧
Would you go ahead and please delete that picture?
你就按一下
You just press...
你有病吧
What is wrong with you?
那别给其他人看  行吗
Could you please not share that with anyone?
我爱给谁看就给谁看
I will share it with whomever I please.
-伙计  -怎么了
- Dude. - Yeah?
你岳母生气了
Marybeth is pissed.
她生什么气
Why?
玛丽贝思
Marybeth?
你还把自己当成返校节国王了
It's like you're the goddamn homecoming king.
我妈妈教导我要礼貌
It was important to my mother that I be polite.
要做个体贴的绅士
I be considerate, I be a gentleman.
你好像玩得还挺开心
It looked like you were having fun.
这对我来说就是场噩梦
I am in a nightmare!
我只是想尽量用一副好脸色
All I'm trying to do is be nice
去面对那些乐意帮忙寻找艾米的人
to the people who are volunteering to help find Amy.
你说得对
You're right.
抱歉
And I'm sorry.
老天爷  这地方闻起来一股屎味儿
My God, this place literally smells like feces.
你搜查时发现什么豪华高尔夫球杆了吗
In your searches, did you find any golf clubs, real fancy?
没
No.
全新的电吉他呢
How about a brand new stratocaster?
也没有
No, nothing like that.
好吧
Well, all right.
这电视有多大  没到65英寸吧
How big's that TV? It's not 65-inch.
远远不到
No, it's nowhere near that.
好的
Okay.
-猫粮呢  -什么
- Kibble? - Excuse me?
他让我顺便把猫喂了
He asked me to feed his cat.
我记得食品柜里有
I saw some in the pantry.
邦妮警探  吉尔平警官  我是诺艾尔·霍桑
Detective Boney, officer Gilpin? Noelle hawthorne!
我知道你们都在屋里
I know y'all are in there!
麻烦你将霍桑小姐
Would you please escort Miss Hawthorne
和她的孩子们请到街上去
and her children back out to the street?
邦妮警探
Detective Boney!
告诉她这可能是犯罪现场
Just remind her it is a possible crime scene.
看看这张大肥脸  妻子失踪还能笑成这样
Look at that pie-eating grin, from a guy whose wife is missing.
-你还好吗  -好得很
- How are you doing? - Terrific.
你岳母呢
How's Marybeth?
她很不爽
She's a wreck.
你呢
And you?
爽爆了
Awesome.
你没瞒着我什么吧
Have you told me everything?
当然没有
Of course.
当真
Everything?
你怎么这么问
Why would you even ask me that?
从艾米失踪那天早晨
Ever since you walked into the bar
你走进我酒吧开始  你看起来就
that morning Amy went missing, you seem...
-不在状态  -当然了
- Off. - I am off.
所有人都跑来质疑我  对我评头论足
Everybody's examining me and projecting their shit on me.
我只想过来跟你喝瓶啤酒
All I want is to come over here, have a beer with you,
清静一会儿
and not be judged.
行吗
Can we do that?
当然
Of course.
你知道我在想什么吗
You know what I keep thinking?
如果妈妈也在这儿
If mom were here?
是啊  就像小时候
Yeah. Like I'm 12.
尼克  要是妈妈还在一定有办法
Nick, mom would fix it.
我该吃药睡觉了
I'm gonna go Benadryl myself to sleep.
-爱你  -爱你
- Love you. - Love you.
我不得不面对一个新的现实
So, here's a strange, new sentence.
2010年9月23日
我现在是密苏里人了
I am a Missourian.
再见  爸爸
Bye, Dad.
没钱  没工作  前途一片灰暗
No money, no jobs, no prospects.
我们收到了马尔的消息
And then, we heard from go.
莫林  我的婆婆
Mama Maureen.
乳腺癌四期
Stage 4 breast cancer.
所以  我们搬去了密苏里州
So, we moved to Missouri.
我倒不介意
I don't mind.
只是希望他至少和我商量一下
I just wish he'd asked.
回到老家的尼克很是开心
Nick is happy to be home.
但我不知道我在会不会扫他的兴
But I don't know if he's happy I'm with him.
我就像他拿错的一件行李
I feel like something he loaded by mistake.
如有必要  丢掉也无妨
Something to be jettisoned, if necessary.
就像一次性的东西
Something disposable.
即便消失了他也不会在意
I feel like I could disappear.
我在门外
天啊
Oh, my God!
-我在电视上看见你了  -好吧
- I saw you on TV. - Okay.
-太疯狂了  -是的
- It's so crazy. - Yeah, I know.
-她就这么消失了  -离家出走而已
- She just vanished? - She's just gone.
-我担心死你了  -你去哪儿了
- I've been so worried about you. - Where have you been?
我给你打了无数次电话  你怎么不接
I called you a hundred times. You gotta pick up your phone!
我在排练
Rehearsals.
什么
What?
《福音》
Godspell.
我姐姐在隔壁睡觉呢
My sister's asleep in the other room.
我想见你
I needed to see you.
我知道  但这太不理智了
I know this is a bad idea.
我至少要听你说爱我
Can you at least tell me you love me?
我是很爱你  但现在咱们必须得处处小心
I do love you, but we have to be really careful right now.
我吓坏了
I've been so scared.
在排练时吗
Between rehearsals?
你让我过好自己的生活
You told me I needed to have my own life.
我知道
I know.
现在不行
We need to stop.
我要你
I need you.
爱抚我
Touch me.
等等  过来
Stop it. Come here.
坐下
Sit down.
好
Okay.
你有没有和别人提过咱俩的事
Did you, by any chance, tell anybody anything about us?
短信中  或者在脸书上
Even in texting, or on Facebook.
脸书  我打电话都用一次性手机
Facebook? I use the disposable phone.
你给我买礼物也都用现金  我不傻  尼克
You buy my presents in cash. I'm not stupid, Nick.
我知道  宝贝
I know, sweetie.
那你是不是留了条红内裤在我办公室
Did you leave a pair of red panties in my office?
可能吧  最好别是别人的
I don't know. Maybe. They better be mine.
宝贝儿  好好想想
Sweetheart, think.
我得回去数数我的红内裤有没有少
I don't know. I'd have to check my red panty inventory.
安迪  现在可不是开玩笑的时候
Andie, I need you to take this seriously, okay?
这是咱俩最后一次见面  直到
This is the last time we're gonna see each other, until...
到什么时候
Until when?
到风声过去
Until it's safe.
你说过要离婚的
You were going to get a divorce.
别再大声说这句话了
Never say that out loud again.
好吧  抱歉
Okay. I'm sorry.
我不想吵架
I don't wanna fight.
我只想和你在一起
I just wanna be with you.
安迪  拜托
Andie, please.
我别无所求
That's all I want.
现在不行
I can't.
这是咱俩最后一次见面
It's our last time together.
春宵一刻值千金
Let's make the most of it.
动作快点儿  完事儿你就得走
Real quick, but then you have to go.
2011年10月2日
我丈夫已经失控了
My husband has come undone.
我们搬到密苏里州陪莫林治病
We moved to Missouri to save Maureen,
但结果却不尽如人愿
but as it turns out, we couldn't.
你能来真是意义重大
It means a lot that you came.
在上流社会受挫后
We took a hit on the brownstone,
我用剩下的信托基金给他买了一个酒吧
and I used the last of my trust fund to buy him a bar.
目前仍然没有盈利
So far, it's just costing money.
尼克有需求时我是他泄欲的工具
Nick uses me for sex when he wants.
其他时候我就跟不存在一样
Otherwise, I don't exist.
今晚我们该进城逛逛
We should go to outback tonight.
听起来不错
That would be nice.
昨晚  绝望的我终于踏出了可悲至极的一步
Last night, I went from desperate to pathetic.
我变成了自己讨厌的人
I became someone I don't even like.
变成了我以前所嘲笑轻视的女人
The kind of woman I used to mock.
你几乎天天出门
You're out so much.
-我知道  -今晚在家待着吧
- I know. - Stay home.
-不行  我已经迟到了  -我能一起去吗
- I can't, I'm already late. - Then, can I come?
你会烦死的
You would hate it.
我那帮高中同学都是大老粗
It's a bunch of my dorky high school friends.
约法三章的  别找借口行吗
Do our code. No bullshit.
不是说好不效仿那些失败的夫妻吗
I thought we weren't gonna be that couple.
好吧  再见
Okay, bye.
-我一直在想  -什么
- Hey, I've been thinking. - Yeah?
一些能带来希望的事
Something positive.
是时候要个孩子了
Maybe it's time.
可现在最不是时候
Now is literally the worst time.
那会是我们的新开始
It would be a new start for us.
对我来说  我才真的有事可做
And for me, I would have a real purpose here.
孩子可不是什么兴趣爱好
A child is not a hobby.
不是兴趣爱好
Not a hobby.
是我的动力
An inspiration.
我们四小时后再争这个  我迟到了
We could have had this fight four hours ago. I'm late.
我不知道你会跟我争
I didn't know it was gonna be a fight.
你真的想变成
You really wanna be the
靠孩子来挽救婚姻的人吗
couple that has a baby to save their marriage?
"挽救"
"Save"?
重启  重组  重燃  管他什么词
Reboot, retool, rekindle, whatever!
-而你现在就要摔门而去  -没错
- And you're gonna walk out the door now? - Yeah!
你他妈就是个懦夫
You're a fucking coward.
不  不能这么下去了
No, it can't go on like this.
真的吗
Really?
-我不准  -你不准
- I won't. - You won't?
你不准  凭什么  这还满足不了你吗
You won't? Why, it's not good enough for you?
差远了
It's not even close!
你个臭婊子
You stupid bitch!
他推开我  我并不害怕
What scared me wasn't that he'd pushed me.
我怕的是他还会怎么伤害我
What scared me was how much he wanted to hurt me more.
怕的是我终将意识到
What scared me was that I'd finally realized,
我惧怕自己的丈夫
I am frightened of my own husband.
要我打电话叫增援吗
You want me to call for backup?
不用了  我会保护你的
Nah, I'll protect you.
天啊
Jesus.
他们应该把这儿烧掉
They ought to burn this place down.
这班家伙也快把这烧掉了
Seems like folks are trying.
你真觉得这儿会有什么吗
You really think this is anything?
从单子上划掉吧
Cross it off the list.
詹森
Hey, Jason.
怎么了  朗达
What's up, Rhonda?
"奉行一切人生来平等的原则"
"And dedicated to the proposition that all men..."
1863年林肯在葛底斯堡发表的演说
有在这附近看见这姑娘吗
Have you seen this girl around here?
为什么要问她
Why do you ask?
她失踪了
She was reported missing.
"是否能够长久存在下去"
"And so dedicated, can long endure."
见过  我记得她
Yeah. I remember her.
她来买什么  大麻  摇头丸
What did she want? Weed, pills?
她来买枪
She wanted a gun.
我告诉她我不卖那玩意儿
I told her it's not my thing.
我也不好受  她看上去相当绝望
I felt bad, though. She seemed really desperate.
她说要很小的  就能近距离开枪了
She said it needed to be small, so she could keep it close.
你确定是她
Are you sure this is her?
在这地方看到那样的姑娘可忘不了
You don't forget a girl like that in here.
她穿着一身粉
She was all in pink.
那天是情人节
It was Valentine's day.
2012年2月14日
情人节我觉得我该买把枪
For Valentine's day, I thought I'd buy a gun.
我都疯成这样子了
That is how crazy I've become.
尼克想要我离开  可又不愿提出离婚
Nick wants me gone but he won't ask for a divorce.
在他看来  我是他酒吧的老板
In his mind, I'm the owner of his bar,
他唯一的资金来源
his only line of credit.
手握婚前协议的贱人
The bitch with the prenup.
我可以回我父母家
I could go home to my parents,
那样我就不得不告诉他们真相
but I'd have to tell them the truth.
可是说出来我自己都不会信
And I don't even know if I believe the truth.
我真觉得尼克会伤害我吗
Can I really think Nick would hurt me?
我开始妄想  太疯狂了
I'm being paranoid. Crazy.
只是
It's just...
有把枪在身边睡得会安稳些
I'd sleep better with a gun.
寻人
艾米·邓恩
七月八日
消失
三天后
糟糕
Oh, shit.
起床了  宝贝  我姐要出来了
Wake up, baby. My sister's gonna come out here.
-抱歉催你这么急  -没关系
- Sorry to rush you. - It's okay.
-来  我帮你  -好
- Here. Let me help you. - Okay.
穿好了
Just get that.
小心点
Be very careful.
我没事
I'm all right.
给你
Here you go.
向我保证每天都要跟我说话
Promise me we'll talk every day.
好的  会的
Okay, we will.
每天都要  尼克  不然我会疯的
Every day, Nick, or I'll go crazy.
不要疯
Don't go crazy.
好的
Okay.
你个死蠢货
You fucking idiot.
你个王八蛋  你他妈当着我的面撒谎
You fucking asshole! You fucking lied to my fucking face!
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
她多大了
How old is she?
二十出头
She's in her early 20s.
有多久了
How long?
-一年半  -你骗了我一年多
- A year and a half. - You lied to me for over a year?
我要是告诉你  你会阻止我的
If I told you, you would have made me stop.
她也太小了
It's so fucking small.
你个大骗子  就跟爸一个德行
You're a liar and a cheat! You're just like dad!
你都怎么认识她的
How did you even meet her?
她是我的学生
She's one of my students.
我还以为作家都讨厌陈词滥调
I thought writers hated cliché.
我不是作家
I'm not a writer.
"呜呜  我被炒了
"Boo-hoo, I got laid off.
我得去操个90后"
I guess I'll fuck a teenager."
不是那样的  好吗
It wasn't like that, okay?
你不知道跟艾米在一起有多惨
You have no idea how shitty it was with Amy.
她弄得我感觉多糟糕
How fucking terrible she made me feel.
我真的郁闷得不行
Flyover boy. I would get knots in my stomach.
回家时  在我都他妈没进门之前
Just coming home, knowing she would be sitting there,
就知道她会那么坐在那儿一脸不满
dissatisfied, before I even walked in the fucking door.
这样太糟糕了
This is so bad.
要是有人发现了  你就完了
If anybody finds out, you're totally fucked.
邦妮在我办公室发现了一条内裤
Boney found a pair of panties in my office,
偶尔安迪和我会在那儿...
where, occasionally, Andie and I...
我都不知道这意味着什么
I don't know what the fuck it means.
你当她们是傻逼吗
Are they super-twat's?
她叫安迪
Her name is Andie.
她也不太确定
She's not entirely sure.
所以你上的这个姑娘
So we are dealing with a 20-year-old,
都20岁了  少条内裤都不知道
who isn't sure where she leaves her undies?
如果不是安迪的  那就是艾米的
If they're not Andie's, that means that they're Amy's,
她刻意留在那儿让我发现的
and she left them there for me to find.
尼克  之前我还替你担惊受怕
Nick, I was scared for you before,
现在我真的是目瞪口呆了
and now, I'm fucking petrified.
我们今晚要为你失踪的妻子守夜
We're having a vigil tonight for your missing wife.
今早你却在跟你的小女友吻别
And this morning, you're kissing your college girlfriend goodbye!
你能想象吗
Can you imagine?
你最近有看电视吗
Have you watched television lately?
有线台的新闻全在播你干的好事
Cable news is all over your shit.
这位酒吧老板犯什么毛病了
I mean, what is wrong with this barkeep?
妻子失踪了
His wife's nowhere to be found,
而这位尼克·邓恩却在与别人调情
and here's Nick Dunne for you, flirting.
拍得不错吧
Cute pic, huh?
-那是谁  -一个可悲的追星族
- Who is that? - Some fucking tragedy groupie.
-那他妈是谁  -我不知道
- Who the fuck is that? - I don't know.
她想给我做派来着
She was trying to give me a casserole.
今天的节目我们请到了辩护律师
On the show today we have defense attorney,
坦纳·博尔特
Tanner Bolt.
杀妻凶手的守护神
Patron Saint to wife-killers everywhere.
坦纳·博尔特
Tanner Bolt,
你真的打算为尼克·邓恩辩护吗
would you actually consider defending Nick Dunne?
一如既往的我想说
Well, let me just say...
埃伦  感谢你如此热情地欢迎我
as always, Ellen, thank you for such a warm welcome.
我当然会为尼克·邓恩辩护
But of course, I'd defend Nick Dunne.
虽然他没有在大家面前痛哭流涕
Listen, just because this guy isn't walking around weeping,
并不代表他就不受伤
that doesn't mean that he's not hurting.
坦纳  反社会的标志之一
Tanner, the hallmark of a sociopath
就是缺乏同情心
is a lack of empathy.
真相是  在这种情况下要显得正常
But the truth is, you'd have to be a sociopath
就太反社会了
to behave normally in this situation.
因为这是世上最不正常的情况
Because it's the most abnormal situation in the world.
坦纳  你是想告诉我这张照片
Tanner, are you trying to tell me that this photo
根本不是正常行为吗
is remotely in the realm of acceptable behavior?
我最讨厌被女人批评攻击了
I'm so sick of being picked apart by women.
你得雇坦纳·博尔特
You need to hire Tanner Bolt.
我不该沦落至此
I don't deserve this.
无罪推定
Innocent until proven guilty.
你就该遭这报应
That's exactly what you deserve.
回去吧  尼克
Go home, Nick.
伙计
Hey, buddy.
我们居然还没逮捕这家伙
I can't believe we haven't arrested this guy.
不能因这金发碧眼的傻瓜的一面之辞
We're not gonna arrest anybody,
我们就去逮捕谁
just because some blonde dunce says so.
你这么给他开脱  爱上他了吗
Why are you going so easy on him? You got a crush?
首先  我是在办案  不是搜捕女巫
One, I am conducting an investigation, not a witch-hunt.
其次  别这么跟我说话  永远不要
And, two, don't talk to me that way, ever.
她想要买枪
She was trying to buy a gun.
我们不知道是谁
We don't know who
或者什么东西吓到她了  吉尔
or what was scaring her, Gil.
汇报最新情况
Give me the update.
目前没有吸毒的可能  这条去掉了
No drug angles panned out yet, so cross that off the list.
我去找了照顾尼克父亲的护士们
I talked to the nurses who care for Nick's father.
那家伙虽是个混蛋  但虚弱到不行
The guy's a bastard, but he's weak as a kitten,
所以也从单子上划去
so cross that off the list.
鲁米诺荧光测试结果  厨房的血迹
So, luminol lit up the kitchen
是七月四日的
like the 4th of July.
血迹相当多
The blood is profuse.
是艾米的  B型
It is Amy's, type B,
很快就能提取出DNA了
and we should have DNA soon.
可能的凶器呢
Thoughts on a weapon?
这痕迹表明是被钝器重击所致
Trajectory indicates blunt force.
也许是根球杆  或是小木棍
Maybe a club or a two-by-four.
她在那儿倒下了  但我怀疑她又爬起来了
She fell there, but I doubt she got back up.
艾米的医疗记录拿到了吗
Amy's medical records come in?
还没有  今晚晚些时候能拿到
No, we'll have them later tonight.
我妻子说他是个杀手
My wife says he's a killer.
好吧  要是蒂凡尼说...
Well, if Tiffany says...
感谢你们都能来
Thank you all for coming out.
唐尼  你还好吗
Hey Donnie, how are you?
里克  非常感谢
Rich, thank you so much.
非常感谢  谢谢你们今晚能来
Thank you, folks. Thank you for being here tonight.
这对我们的家庭意义重大
It just means the world to our family.
对艾米也是
And to Amy.
大家都知道
As you all know,
我的妻子  艾米·艾略特·邓恩
my wife, Amy Elliott Dunne.
三天前失踪了
disappeared three days ago.
我恳求任何知道相关信息的人
And I want to implore anyone who has any information at all.
请站出来  帮助我们
Please come forward. Help us.
太性感了
So hot.
他太可怕了
He is so creepy.
我想说几句
I wanna say something,
因为我觉得你们也许会有疑问
because I think some of you might be wondering,
却又出于礼貌不便提出
and are too polite to ask.
我与我妻子的失踪毫不相干
I had nothing to do with the disappearance of my wife.
我正配合警方调查
I'm cooperating with the police.
我也没有雇律师
I haven't hired a lawyer.
我没什么好隐瞒的
I have nothing to hide.
艾米是我的灵魂伴侣
Amy is my soul mate.
她美丽
She is brilliant,
迷人而又睿智
she's charming, and wise.
我爱你  艾米
I love you, Amy.
混蛋
Asshole.
我爱我的妻子
I love my wife.
十分地爱
So much.
也许我没有为了媒体的镜头而故作姿态
And I may not behave for the cameras the way they want me to,
如果他们想以此惩罚我  我没意见
and if they wanna punish me for that, that's okay.
但我想请求那些媒体人  请来骚扰我
But I just wanna ask you in the media, please, harass me,
但不要去骚扰这儿的人
but don't harass the people of this town.
要嘲弄就嘲弄我吧
If you need to mock somebody, mock me.
尼克
Nick!
请不要把调查当儿戏
But please don't turn this investigation into a circus.
你妻子在哪儿  尼克
Where's your wife, Nick?
让警察去做他们的工作
Let the police do their jobs.
你对你怀孕的妻子做了什么
What did you do to your pregnant wife?
你告诉他们了吗  尼克
Did you tell them that, Nick?
你告诉他们艾米已经怀孕六周了吗
Did you tell them Amy was six weeks pregnant?
感谢大家今晚的支持
Thank you for your support tonight.
让我们一起寻找艾米
Let's find Amy.
继续吧  如果你们想说点什么
Go ahead, if you guys wanna say something.
吉尔  快去
Gil, go, go.
尼克  你去哪儿
Nick, where are you going?
拦住他
Stop him!
现在不接受提问  谢谢
No questions right now. Thank you.
你为什么要逃走
Why are you running away?
别跑
Don't run.
大家不要过来
Everybody, stay back.
大伙  不要拍了  你们知道规矩的
Guys, come on. You know better.
别踩草坪  从路缘上下来
Get off the grass, get down to the curb.
-吉尔  -交给我
- Hey, Gil. - On it.
好了
All right.
好了  听她的  不许拍照
All right, y'all heard her. No pictures.
谁
Hello?
操
Fuck.
你吓到我了  要喝一杯吗
You scared me. Want a drink?
你知道她怀孕了吗
Did you know she was pregnant?
我跟你说了
I told you,
诺艾尔·霍桑就他妈疯了
Noelle Hawthorne is fucking crazy.
她都不认识艾米
She doesn't even know Amy.
我看她们是对好闺蜜呢
They look like pretty good friends to me.
我不知道
Look, I don't know.
但这也证明不了她怀孕了
But it certainly doesn't prove that she's pregnant.
我们很快就能拿到她的医疗记录了
We have her medical records coming.
-好  -趁这会我们聊聊
- Good. - So, let's talk while we wait.
先从这边开始  犯罪现场
Let's start over here. The scene of the crime.
我们见过不少私闯民宅的现场
You see, we've seen dozens of home invasions.
数都数不清
Dozens and dozens.
这块区域  我们一看见就觉得不对劲
This area right here, it looked wrong from the second we saw it.
一切都像是刻意摆出来的  看
The whole thing looked staged. Watch this.
经历了一番生死搏斗
And yet, they remained upright
却还能这么井然有序
throughout this life-and-death struggle?
我不知道  你想要我说什么
I don't know. What do you want me to say?
你妻子失踪后你有打扫过房子吗
Did you do any housekeeping the day your wife went missing?
没有
No.
因为我们的人做了荧光测试
Because our guys did a luminol test.
很遗憾地告诉你  厨房那片可亮了
And I'm sorry to tell you, but that kitchen lit up.
艾米在那儿流了很多血
Amy lost a lot of blood in there,
尼克  很多
Nick. A lot.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
没错  接着有人给拖掉了
Yeah, and then somebody mopped it up.
等一下
Wait a second.
如果他们想要制造犯罪现场
Why would they mop up the blood,
为什么还要把血给拖掉
if they're trying to stage a crime scene?
没有血  也没有尸体  就意味着绑架
No blood and no body suggests kidnapping.
也就告诉我们去调查外面的人
It tells us, look at people outside the house.
就像你一直在提的那些流浪汉
Like these homeless you keep mentioning.
一地的血  没有尸体  则意味着谋杀
A pool of blood and no body suggests homicide.
那我们就要调查家里的人
It tells us to look at people inside the house.
我们来就是为了这个  尼克
Which is what we're doing here, Nick.
我知道了
I see.
所以你的婚姻情况如何  尼克
So, how was your marriage, Nick?
因为现在  只有诺艾尔的描述
Because right now, all we got is Noelle.
她说  "不好"
She says, "Not good."
吉尔  你和你妻子都因为些什么起争执
Gil, what do you and your wife argue about?
-什么最让你生气  -钱  缺钱
- What pisses you off? - Money, lack thereof.
我和我前任也是一样
Me and my ex, it's the same.
之所以提这个
I mention that
是因为我们看了你的财务状况  尼克
because we got a look at your finances, Nick.
十一万七千美元的信用卡债务
$117,000 in credit card debt.
-什么  -我调了些你买的东西的清单
- What? - I pulled up some of the merchandise.
都是这些大手笔的挥霍
There are these fun little splurges.
这些东西我都没买过
I didn't buy any of this stuff.
我都不打高尔夫
I don't even golf!
我打  你买的都是好球杆
I do! You bought great clubs.
我喜欢机器狗
I like the robot dog.
这是身份盗窃  这是重罪
This is identity theft! This is a felony!
我们得查出是谁干的
We need to find out who did this!
好吧  那我们谈谈人寿保险
All right. Let's talk about life insurance.
在四月份
Because in April,
你把艾米的人寿保险保额突然提高到了
you bumped up Amy's life insurance
一百二十万
to $1.2 million.
我是提高了
Yes, I did.
那是她的主意  她要我提高的
That was her idea. She wanted me to.
文书的字都是你签的
You filed the paperwork.
是她让我签的
Because she told me to!
等一等
Hold on a sec.
嗯  好的
Yeah? Okay.
你确定
For sure?
好吧
All right.
她是怀孕了
She was pregnant.
这事太扯了
This is insane.
那么我的问题就变成了...
So, my question becomes...
我不会再跟你说话了
I don't want to talk to you again, ever.
除非有律师在场
Without a lawyer.
马尔
Margo!
等一下  让我说完
Just hold on a second. Let me finish.
尼克
Nick?
我听到了  我听到了  我也很惊讶
I hear you, I hear you. I was as surprised as...
我知道你不开心  我也不知道她怀孕了
I know you're upset. I had no idea she was pregnant.
我也是这么想的  但显然...
Listen, I thought so, too, but evidently that wasn't...
你想知道真相吗
you want to know the truth?
真相就是艾米不想要孩子
The truth is, Amy didn't want kids.
对  我也很震惊
Well, I'm as surprised as...
你跟我说是你不想要孩子的
you told me you didn't want kids.
我可不想吵架
I was trying to put a good face on.
结果你老婆突然就怀孕了
Then, suddenly, you've got a pregnant wife.
这下你的问题严重了
That's a problem for you.
再加上那个秘密小情人
Especially when you factor in the secret teenage girlfriend.
拜托  别再看艾伦·阿伯特的节目了
Oh, stop watching Ellen Abbott!
那你他妈就告诉我事实
You have to fucking talk to me!
我没跟你说她不想要孩子
I didn't tell you that she didn't want kids,
是因为她不想让别人知道  好吗
because she didn't want me to. OK?
因为那样你们又会多一条恨她的理由
Because it would have just been another reason for you to hate her.
理由已经够多了  这样比较简单...
And we had enough of those already! It was easier to just...
-骗我吗  -我想要孩子
- lie to me? - I wanted kids!
我们刚搬来的时候  我去过人工受孕诊所
When we first moved here, I went to a fertility clinic!
-没成功吗  -我做了我那一半
- It didn't work? - I did my part!
打飞机吗
Masturbate.
轮到艾米做她那一半的时候
When it came time for Amy to do her thing,
突然她就说
all of a sudden it was like...
"我不清楚诶  还是别做了吧"
"Well, I don't know. Maybe. No, thanks."
现在还有谁会相信你的话
Now, who would believe you?
好吧
All right.
这是诊所寄来的信
This is a letter from the clinic.
告诉我他们要销毁我的精子
Notifying me that they're gonna destroy my sample,
除非我联系他们
unless I contact them.
我把信给了艾米
So, I gave it to Amy.
第二天却在垃圾桶里找到了它
The next day, I saw it in the trash.
可是那时候你已经和安迪好上了吧
But you were already with Andie by then, right?
我想和艾米要个孩子
I wanted a baby with Amy.
如果一年前艾米能怀孕的话
A year ago, Amy being pregnant
那就再好不过了
would have been the best thing ever!
"当你可怜的艾米染上风寒  甜点也..."
"When your poor Amy has a cold, this dessert just..."
这是你没解开的提示
this is the clue you couldn't solve.
对
Yeah.
德西寄来的信
A letter from Desi.
是艾米的那个变态前男友吗
That creepy boyfriend of Amy's?
对  那个愿意为她赴汤蹈火的大款
Yeah, it was the fucking rich guy who would do anything for her.
老是看到他的名字  真是恶心
It just kept hanging over my head. It was disgusting.
你们的婚前协议
Your prenup?
尼克  你为啥收着这些东西
Nick, why have you kept this stuff?
你的恨意都在这个盒子里了
It's like a little box of hate.
不知道  也许我确实恨她
I don't know, go! Maybe I hate her!
不管怎样我都爱你
I love you no matter what.
但是你必须告诉我
But you need to tell me.
告诉你什么
Tell you what?
你想问我什么
What are you asking me?
你是要问我有没有杀我老婆吗  马尔
Are you asking me if I killed my wife, go?
你是要问我这个吗  我有没有杀我老婆
Is that what you're asking me? If I murdered my wife?
我不会问你这种问题的
I would never ask you that!
马尔
Margo!
别踩到玻璃
Don't walk on the glass.
你啥都不知道对吧
You have no clue, do you?
线索三
他那天为什么过来
Why was he here that night?
他的老婆失踪了  为什么要到这儿来
His wife is missing. Why come here?
谁在乎呢
Who cares?
朗达  我们已经破案了
Rhonda, we got this.
逮捕他吧
Let's make the arrest.
你知道没有尸体要立谋杀案有多难吗
Do you know how hard it is to make a murder case without a body?
不知道
No.
非常难
Well, it's incredibly hard.
所以  我还需要一样东西
So, I want one last thing.
什么东西
What's that?
尸体
I want a body.
想象我是个很坏很坏的女孩
Picture me. I'm a girl who's very, very bad.
小心
Be careful.
我必须受到惩罚  活该被逮个正着
I need to be punished, and by "Punished," I mean "Had."
坏
惩罚
皮鞭
锁链
该死
Fuck.
五周年纪念的东西都在那里
It's where you keep goodies for anniversary five.
快打开门吧
So, open the door.
木头
惩罚  木头  沙滩
Punish. Wood. Beach.
进来瞧一瞧
And look alive.
惩罚  木头
Punish. Wood.
木头
Wood.
我会试着相信我的丈夫爱我
I will practice believing my husband loves me,
也会爱这个孩子
and will love this baby.
相信这个孩子也许能拯救我们的婚姻
That this child might really save our marriage.
但也许我错了
But I could be wrong.
因为有时候
Because sometimes,
他看我的眼神
the way he looks at me,
让我感觉
I think.
我的梦中情人
Man of my dreams.
我孩子的父亲
Father of my child.
我的丈夫  也许会杀了我
This man of mine may kill me.
他也许真的会
He may truly
杀了我
Kill me.
我的天
WTF?
现在我死了  我觉得开心多了
I am so much happier now that I'm dead.
七月五日
清
晨
理论上说还是"失踪"
Technically, "Missing."
但很快就会判定我死亡了
Soon to be presumed dead.
消失了
Gone.
而我那懒惰  撒谎  劈腿
And my lazy, lying, cheating,
还蒙在鼓里的丈夫
oblivious husband,
会因为谋杀我而锒铛入狱
will go to prison for my murder.
尼克·邓恩夺走了我的骄傲与尊严
Nick Dunne took my pride and my dignity,
还有我的希望和财产
and my hope and my money.
他不停向我索取  直到我不再存在
He took and took from me until I no longer existed.
这就是谋杀
That's murder.
让他得到应有的惩罚吧
Let the punishment fit the crime.
要伪造一出以假乱真的谋杀  必须非常严谨
To fake a convincing murder, you have to have discipline.
和一个蠢货邻居交朋友
You befriend a local idiot.
倾听她无聊生活的各种细节
Harvest the details of her humdrum life.
不停地跟她提起你老公的暴脾气
And cram her with stories about your husban's violet temper.
秘密地制造财政危机
Secretly create some money troubles.
刷爆信用卡  网上赌博也可以
Credit cards, perhaps online gambling.
趁他不注意
With the help of the unwitting,
提高自己的保险金额
bump up your life insurance.
购买逃走用的车  去二手交易网站
Purchase getaway car. Craigslist.
买便宜的普通车  现金交易
Generic. Cheap. Pay cash.
你需要包装自己
You need to package yourself
这样你走了大家才会觉得可惜
so that people will truly mourn your loss.
美国人最爱的就是孕妇了
And America loves pregnant women.
就好像滚个床单很难一样
As if it's so hard to spread your legs.
知道真正难的是什么吗
You know what's hard?
如何抽干马桶
伪造怀孕
Faking a pregnancy.
首先  抽干你的马桶
First, drain your toilet.
邀请怀孕的蠢货去你家
Invite pregnant idiot into your home,
给她狂灌柠檬汁
and ply her with lemonade.
窃取怀孕的蠢货的尿
Steal pregnant idiot's urine.
收工
Voilà.
在医疗记录里  你已经怀孕了
A pregnancy is now part of your legal medical record.
周年纪念日快乐
Happy anniversary.
等着对这事毫无察觉的老公
Wait for your clueless husband
出门上班
To start his day.
他走啦
Off he goes.
现在时间紧迫
And the clock is ticking.
一丝不苟地布置犯罪现场
Meticulously stage your crime scene,
留下足够让人起疑的破绽
with just enough mistakes to raise the specter of doubt.
你需要流血
You need to bleed.
很多血
A lot.
非常非常多
A lot, a lot.
像是头被打破了一样
A head wound kind of bleed.
犯罪现场才会有的血迹
A crime scene kind of bleed.
擦血迹  但不能擦干净
You need to clean poorly
就像是他做的
Like he would.
擦干  流血  流血  擦干
Clean and bleed. Bleed and clean.
再留下一些线索
And leave a little something behind.
七月还点壁炉
A fire in July?
因为你是你
And because you're you,
仅仅这些是不够的
you don't stop there.
你需要一本日记
You need a diary.
至少三百条关于尼克和艾米的故事
Minimum, 300 entries on the Nick and Amy story.
先从童话般的热恋说起
Start with the fairy tale early days.
那些都是真的  真实得残忍
Those are true. And they're crucial.
必须把尼克和艾米写得非常可爱
You want Nick and Amy to be likeable.
然后  开始编造
After that, you invent.
花天酒地
The spending.
虐待和恐惧
The abuse. The fear.
威胁使用暴力
The threat of violence.
尼克还觉得自己是作家呢
And Nick thought he was the writer.
烧掉刚刚好的一部分
Burn it just the right amount.
确定警察能找到它
Make sure the cops will find it.
最后  尊重传统  布置特别的寻宝游戏
Finally, honor tradition with a very special treasure hunt.
如果我不出错  全世界都会憎恨尼克
And if I get everything right, the world will hate Nick,
七月五日
失踪
两小时后
因为他杀了自己美丽的孕妇妻子
for killing his beautiful, pregnant wife.
在愤怒平息后  当我准备好时
And after all the outrage, when I'm ready,
我会吃上一把安眠药  然后跳进水里
I'll go out on the water with a handful of pills,
口袋里装满石头
and a pocket full of stones.
当他们找到我的尸体  他们会认为
And when they find my body, they'll know,
尼克·邓恩像扔垃圾一样抛弃了他的妻子
Nick Dunne dumped his beloved like garbage.
而她则缓缓飘落  飘过那些
And she floated down past all the other
受尽凌辱  无人理会  无处求援的女人
Abused, unwanted, inconvenient women.
然后  尼克也会死去
Then, Nick will die, too.
尼克和艾米会彻底消失
Nick and Amy will be gone.
不过  我们也从没存在过
But, then, we never really existed.
尼克爱上的只是我扮演的女孩罢了
Nick loved a girl I was pretending to be.
"好妹子"
"Cool girl."
男人总是这么拍女孩马屁  不是吗
Men always use that, don't they? As their defining compliment.
"她是个好妹子"
"She's a cool girl."
好妹子很性感
Cool girl is hot.
好妹子热情勇敢
Cool girl is game.
好妹子幽默风趣
Cool girl is fun.
好妹子从不对她的男人生气
Cool girl never gets angry at her man.
她只会露出谦卑又忠诚的微笑
She only smiles in a chagrined, loving manner
然后把嘴凑上去被操
And then presents her mouth for fucking.
她喜欢他爱的一切
She likes what he likes.
她的男人肯定是个喜欢色情漫画的音乐迷
So evidently, he's a vinyl hipster who loves fetish manga.
如果他喜欢狂野的女孩  她就是个时尚潮女
If he likes girls gone wild, she's a mall babe,
会在猫头鹰餐厅忍受着辣翅大聊橄榄球
who talks football and endures buffalo wings at Hooters.
遇到尼克·邓恩的时候  我知道他想要个好妹子
When I met Nick Dunne, I knew he wanted cool girl.
我承认  我愿意为了他尝试一次
And for him, I'll admit, I was willing to try.
我用蜜蜡刮掉了我的阴毛
I wax-stripped my pussy raw.
我喝着罐装啤酒看亚当·桑德勒的喜剧
I drank canned beer watching Adam Sandler movies.
我吃冷掉的披萨  保持完美身材
I ate cold pizza and remained a size two.
基本上定期给他口交
I blew him semi-regularly.
我活在当下
I lived in the moment.
我他妈享受人生
I was fucking game.
不能说我一点儿都不喜欢那样
I can't say I didn't enjoy some of it.
尼克发掘了我性格中从未出现过的部分
Nick teased out of me things I didn't know existed.
温和  幽默  轻松
A lightness, a humor, an ease.
但我也让他变得更聪明  更锋利
But I made him smarter. Sharper.
让他成为了和我旗鼓相当的对手
I inspired him to rise to my level.
我造就了自己的梦中情人
I forged the man of my dreams.
七月五日
失踪
十小时后
我们乐于扮演别人
We were happy pretending to be other people.
我们是最幸福的夫妻
We were the happiest couple we knew.
如果不是最幸福的一对
And what's the point of being together,
那还在一起干什么呢
if you're not the happiest?
可尼克变得懒惰
But Nick got lazy.
变成了我绝不会嫁给的男人
He became someone I did not agree to marry.
他居然希望我无条件地爱他
He actually expected me to love him unconditionally.
然后他把身无分文的我
Then he dragged me, penniless,
拖来了中部的穷乡僻壤
to the navel of this great country
给自己找了个更新鲜  更年轻  更活泼的
And found himself a newer, younger, bouncier
好妹子
Cool girl.
我会看着他毁掉我
You think I'd let him destroy me
然后自己去过幸福生活吗
And end up happier than ever?
门都没有
No fucking way.
他不会赢的
He doesn't get to win.
我可爱  有魅力  正直的密苏里男生
My cute, charming, salt-of-the-earth, Missouri guy.
他需要上一课
He needed to learn.
成年人会努力争取
Grown-ups work for things.
成年人会付出努力
Grown-ups pay.
成年人会承担后果
Grown-ups suffer consequences.
等一下
Wait.
给我二十秒  不要责备我或者打断我
I need 20 seconds where you don't judge me, interrupt me
也别生气
Or get angry.
好吧
Okay.
这是信用卡账单上的那些东西吗
Is that all the stuff from the credit cards?
五周年纪念的东西都放哪了
Where do you store goodies for anniversary five?
木婚
Wood.
-所以是小木屋  -我的小木屋
- Woodshed. - Yeah, my woodshed.
那个该死的贱人
That fucking bitch.
-我还以为...  -没关系
- I thought... - It's all right.
换我也会那么想
I would have, too.
那礼物是什么
What's that present?
不知道
I don't know.
打开看看吧
Let's find out.
"亲爱的老公  我知道
"Dear husband, I know
你以为自己可以在这个世界上为所欲为
You think you're moving through this world unseen.
别再这么想了
Don't believe that for a second.
我知道你去过哪里  也知道你将要去哪里
I know where you've been, and I know where you're going.
这个纪念日  我安排了一次旅行
For this anniversary, I've arranged a trip.
沿着河流  一直向上
Follow the river, up, up, up.
好好享受吧  因为你已经完蛋了
Sit back and relax, because you are done."
"沿河向上"是什么意思
What's "Up, up river"?
进监狱的意思
"Up the river." Prison.
这贱人真他妈疯了
Fucking crazy bitch.
原来是这样
That's what this is.
她想诬陷我谋杀了她
She's framing me for her murder.
你娶了个变态啊
You married a complete psychopath.
周年纪念那天早上
The morning of our anniversary
我想跟她提离婚的  我实在受不了了
I was gonna ask her for a divorce. I just couldn't do it.
没办法再假装下去  一天都不行
I couldn't fake it for another year, another day.
结果呢
Then what happened?
在我开口以前  她说
Before I could say anything, she said,
"我希望你出去静一静
"I need you to go somewhere,
想想我们的婚姻"
and really think about our marriage."
她知道我会去索耶沙滩
She knew I would go to Sawyer beach.
这样你就没有不在场证明了
So you'd have no alibi.
她一步步操纵了我
She stage-managed me.
她知道我会怎么做  我他妈还真的那么做了
She knew exactly what I would do. And I fucking did it.
我去了沙滩  思考了我们的婚姻
I went to the beach, I thought about our marriage.
决定回去提出离婚
I came back and decided I wanted a divorce.
但等你到家的时候
And by the time you got home,
她已经不见了
she was gone.
-真他妈的  -她真厉害
- You fuck! - She's good.
想到她不在了
Part of me was relieved
我有点解脱了的感觉
when I thought she was gone.
潘趣与朱迪的木偶
Punch and Judy puppets.
记得吗  他把朱迪打死  又杀了孩子
Remember, he beats Judy to death and kills that baby.
所以我是潘趣咯
So I'm punch.
这我们都知道了
We already knew that.
艾米  你想表达什么
Amy, what's your point?
密苏里州有死刑吗
Does Missouri have the death penalty?
七月六日
消失
一天后
自杀
把车丢掉
没有指纹
擦干净
丢掉所有东西
自杀
寻找丢车地点
在艾伦·阿伯特的网站发匿名留言
邻居你好啊
Hey, neighbor.
我已经好几周没见到正常的邻居了
It's been weeks since I had anyone decent next door.
我可不知道自己算不算正常
Well, I don't know how decent I feel.
只要你不养蛇
As long as you don't own a python,
或者在凌晨四点放死亡金属
and blast death metal at 4 am,
咱们就能成好闺蜜
we're gonna be best friends.
好吧  很高兴认识你
All right. Nice meeting you.
我是格蕾塔
I'm Greta.
我是南希
I'm Nancy.
你要去码头吗  我需要涂点防晒霜
Are you going to the marina? I could use some creamer.
抱歉  我帮不了你
I'm sorry. I can't.
我还有事要做
I've got work to do.
好吧  回头见
All right. See you around!
会的
You will.
七月七日
失踪
两天后
艾伦·阿伯特
快  让我看看你的专属亲切微笑
Come on. Show me that darling Nicky smile.
你个混蛋
You asshole.
七月七日
失踪
三天后
南希
Nancy.
今天又热起来了
It's hot again today.
你从哪来的
So, where are you from?
我猜猜
Let me guess.
内布拉斯加州
Nebraska.
是新奥尔良市
New Orleans.
如果要涂防晒油  我技术很好的
You know, I am an expert oiler.
我猜也是
Oh, I just bet you are.
润肤乳和香精  还有防晒霜
Lotions and balms. Ointment.
你们被晒黑了我可是会心疼的
I would hate for y'all to get tan lines.
真贴心
So sweet.
好吧  你们知道到哪里可以找到我
Okay. You know where I'll be.
看来我们挑男人的眼光一致啊
I see we have the same taste in men.
那种眼光已经被我丢进浴室的柜子里了
I clipped it on a bathroom cabinet.
至少你可以不必为他保守秘密了
Least you could do is not keep his secrets for him.
我猜猜看
Let me guess.
他想看比赛  而你却在旁边唠叨个没完
He's trying to watch the big game and you just won't shut up.
不对  你看起来不像是话多的人
No, you don't seem like much of a talker.
我懂了
I got it.
你男人被你捉奸在床
You caught your boy rubbing up on some hot little skank,
他也搅了你的好事  当做礼尚往来
and he apologized to you by busting you a good one.
更糟糕
Worse.
更糟吗
Worse?
我去他上班的酒吧想给他一个惊喜
I went to the bar where he works to surprise him.
结果他和一个
And out he comes with
完全不该出现在酒吧的女孩出来了
this girl who had no business being in a bar.
我们相识的第一个晚上
On the very first night that we met,
走过一家在卸糖霜的面包店
we walked by a bakery that was having their sugar delivered.
漫天都是糖霜  到处都是
And it was in the air, everywhere.
像一场糖霜暴风雪
A sugar storm.
他第一次吻我之前
And before he kissed me,
他俯过身
he leaned in,
做了这个动作
and did this.
-猜猜怎么着  -怎么了
- And guess what. - What?
他对她做了同样的动作
He did the exact same thing with her.
这是我听过的最让我恶心的事了
That is the most disgusting thing I ever heard.
谢谢你
Thank you.
非常感谢
Thanks very much.
好了  我们成焦点了
Well, we've gone mainstream.
七月九日
失踪
四天后
这是上诉程序  我们会尝试起诉他们
It's an appeals process, so we will attempt to appeal to them.
博尔特先生  坦纳·博尔特
Mr. Bolt. Tanner Bolt?
尼克·邓恩
Nick Dunne.
我一直在等你的电话  我的朋友
I have been sitting by the phone, my friend.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你不相信我吗
Do you not believe me?
不  我相信  但这是我听过的最疯狂的事
No, I believe you. It's just the craziest thing I've ever heard.
我挺喜欢的  但对你来说  糟糕透顶
I love it. But, for you, it sucks.
但这种情况下你不是应该
But you gotta have a grudging respect
向她的手段致敬吗
for your wife at this point, right?
-你是想把我嘲笑出去吗  -不
- Are you laughing me out of the building? - No!
开什么玩笑  案子我接了
Are you kidding me? I'm in.
必须接
I'm way in.
你找对人了  我就接这种案子  尼克
You came to the right guy. This is what I do, Nick.
所以我的定金是十万
This is why I have a $100,000 retainer.
我能打赢"必输"的官司
I win the unwinnable cases.
十万
$100,000?
这个我们可以想办法
We'll figure something out.
我会给你一个特别的
I'll give you a special
"我的妻子深谙复仇之术"折扣
"My wife is skilled in the art of vengeance" Rate.
好吧
Okay.
那么  打算怎么办
So, what's the plan?
眼下  是双方各执一词的阶段
Well, right now, it's a "He said, she said."
-她说的故事比我的好  -不  尼克
- She's telling a better story. - No, Nick.
她讲诉的故事堪称完美
She is telling the perfect story.
所以今天我们就要开始
So, we need to start today
准备你的辩词  如果用得上的话
to prepare your defense, should we need it.
-而如果我们决定采用你的版本  -真相
- And if we decide to go with your version of... - The truth.
那我们需要改变公众对艾米的看法
Then we'll need to realign the public's perception of Amy.
不能再让他们把她当美国甜心
Make them stop seeing her as America's sweetheart,
而是看清她的本质
and see her for what she is,
一个善于操纵别人思想的人
which a mind-fucker of the first degree.
现在  这是个浩大的改观工程
Now, that is a huge realignment.
除你之外  我们还需要其他人的声音
We'll need other voices besides yours.
必须有一个人
There has to be someone out there
曾经吃过她苦头的人
that she's screwed with in the past.
有个纽约人  叫汤米·欧哈拉
There's a New York guy. O'Hara, Tommy O'Hara.
八年前  她起诉过他
Eight years ago, she pressed charges against him.
那应该很容易找到
That should be easy to find.
曾经的同学  德西·柯林斯
Ex-classmate, Desi Collings.
她说他跟踪过她  他住在圣路易斯
She said that he stalked her. He's in St. Louis.
你去找汤米  我去起草合同
You go talk to Tommy, and I'll draw up the contract.
和你说了  你找对人了
I told you, you came to the right guy.
是的
Apparently.
汤米
Tommy?
我是
Yeah.
-谢谢你来见我  -没事
- Thanks for seeing me. - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
你需要喝点东西
You're gonna want a drink.
对
Yeah.
她说你对她动粗了
So, she said you got physical with her.
不  哥们  她说我强奸她
No, dude, she said I raped her.
强奸是一级重罪
First degree, felony rape.
-你做了吗  -你呢
- Did you do it? - Did you do it?
可能要蹲30年大牢  甚至终身监禁
I was looking at 30 years to life.
-你有被庭审过吗  -他妈的根本没有
- Did you get a trial? - Fuck, no.
我看起来像能吃牢饭的人吗
Do I look like I would do well in the yard?
我做了个辩诉交易  只是性侵  无需入狱
I pled down, man. Sexual assault one, no jail time.
-那也不是小事  -是啊
- That's something. - Oh, yeah.
这八年来我都找不到工作
I've been unemployed for the last eight years,
因为我必须在每一份求职信上
because I have to write
注明我曾性侵他人
"Sexual offender" on every job application.
邻里监督组织那里也有我的名字
I'm on a neighborhood watch list,
因为我不得不报备自己是名危险分子
because I have to register as a predator.
我快十年没交过女朋友了
I haven't had a date in almost a decade,
因为只要她们上网搜索我...
because if a girl googles me...
你能和我说说这是怎么回事吗
Could you walk me through what happened?
我在这场派对上认识了艾米
I meet Amy at this party, you know?
我们一拍即合  她很完美
We click. She's perfect.
漂亮  聪明  又博览群书
She's beautiful, she's smart, she's well-read.
还有二十岁脱衣舞娘的妖娆身材
She's got an ass like a 20-year-old stripper.
我想  "这里面有什么内幕"
I think, "What's the catch?"
几个月之后  我才想到  这事不会善了
A few months, it hits me. This is not going to be easy.
女生就像需要修缮的房屋  但是艾米
Girls like a fixer-upper, but Amy?
我成了她的附属物  她把我当成她的东西
She annexed me. She made me her business.
有点过分了  她出去给我买领带
It was just too much. She went out and bought me ties.
我们至少去了二十趟
And we must have gone 20 rounds over that.
就买个领带  这整件事变得...
Ties. The whole thing just became...
-所以你和她分手  -不  我只是躲着她
- So, you broke up with her. - No, I just backed away.
给她点空间  没什么大不了  对吧
Gave her some space. No big deal, right?
我是这么想的
So I thought.
后来有天晚上  艾米来我家
Then one night, Amy comes over to my place,
带了一瓶波旁威士忌和我喜欢的乐队的盗版碟
with a bottle of Bourbon and a bootleg of this band I love.
不到两分钟  她把我内裤脱了
And within two minutes, she's got my pants around my ankles,
然后她跪着  然后...
and she is kneeling down, and...
抱歉  我知道她是你妻子
I'm sorry. I know it's your wife.
-你们做爱了  -对  两厢情愿的
- You had sex? - Yeah, consensual.
很激烈  但那是她强烈要求的
It was rough, but she was screaming for it.
第二天早上  两名警察来敲我的门
Next morning, there's two cops at my door.
艾米的受伤情况与强奸吻合
Amy has wounds that are consistent with rape.
手腕上被捆的痕迹  还有我的精液
Ligature marks on her wrist, and my semen.
看起来就像我把艾米绑在床上  强奸了她
It looks like I've tied Amy to my bed, and raped her.
说是我干的
Me!
然后  猜猜他们找到了什么
And then, guess what they find.
我床上的床头架  一边一条
Headboards of my bed, one on each side.
那种你不会戴的领带
The ties you wouldn't wear.
你果然了解你的妻子
You do know your wife.
-你后来有见过她吗  -有
- Did you ever see her again? - Yeah.
上周  在电视上  你也在
On TV, last week, with you.
我在想
I thought,
"艾米
"There's Amy.
她从被强奸晋级为被谋杀了"
She's graduated from being raped to being murdered."
你也在看这个吗
You been watching this, too?
昨晚的爆炸性消息
Last night's bombshell.
我们刚发现
We just found out,
艾米·艾略特·邓恩在失踪时确实怀孕了
Amy Elliott Dunne was, indeed, pregnant when she went missing.
凯莉·卡布丁娜  这事让我想吐
Kelly Capitono, this makes me wanna throw up.
一个怀孕的女人
What is it about a pregnant woman,
一个身体里孕育着生命的女人
a woman carrying life inside her,
却让男人变成了禽兽
that turns men into animals?
艾伦  这种情况不少见
Ellen, this is an epidemic.
男友或者丈夫的毒手
The third leading cause of death among pregnant women
是孕妇的第三大死因
is homicide committed by a boyfriend or husband.
我们绝不要忘记这位妻子
Let's not forget about the wife, ever.
今晚  我们欢迎艾米的挚友  诺艾尔·霍桑
Tonight, we welcome Amy's best friend, Noelle Hawthorne.
谢谢你来参加节目  诺艾尔
Thanks for being on the show, Noelle.
谢谢  艾伦
Thank you, Ellen.
请容我说一句
And let me just say this...
艾米会感谢你的  还有你为女性所作的一切
Amy would have loved you, and all you do for women.
真感动
Oh, that's nice.
和我们聊聊你的朋友吧  诺艾尔
Why don't you tell us about your friend, Noelle?
艾米待人非常友善
Amy was so nurturing.
谁能说出来  哪怕就一次
Oh, I'd love if just once, someone was like,
"她就是个小婊子"
"She was a real rag."
她美丽  聪慧而且善良
She was beautiful and smart and kind.
我看像个有钱的贱人
Seems like a rich bitch to me.
你什么意思  大家都喜欢她
What do you mean? People love her.
不知道  她看起来很傲慢
I don't know. She seems uppity.
被宠坏的富家女孩  嫁给了一个骗子
Spoiled rich girl, married a cheating asshole.
付出了最大的代价
Paid the ultimate price.
唯一的秘密是她的丈夫  我们从未见过尼克
The only secret was her husband. We never met Nick.
他从没介绍过自己
He never introduced himself.
为什么呢  诺艾尔  你觉得是为什么呢
Why was that, Noelle? Why do you think?
我想我们都知道原因
I think we know why.
因为他脾气非常暴躁
Because he had a violent temper.
这话有点刻薄了
A little harsh.
这就是生活啊  宝贝
That's life, baby.
他知道我已经看透了他
He knew I'd have seen right through him.
别误会我
Don't get me wrong.
我不是说  他就可以杀害她
I'm not saying it's okay he killed her.
我只是说  事情是有原因的
I'm just saying, there are consequences.
真爽
Fuck, yeah.
她那么孤单
She was so alone.
而且她那么无辜
And she was so innocent.
你是个很好的朋友  诺艾尔
You're a good friend, Noelle.
你也是我们节目的好朋友
And you're a good friend of the show.
谢谢你来参加节目
Thanks for coming on.
请告诉我你搞定了坦纳·博尔特
Please tell me you landed Tanner Bolt.
是坦纳·博尔特搞定了我
Tanner Bolt landed me.
回去的路上我会联系德西·柯林斯
I'm gonna try and see Desi Collings on my way home.
还有  马尔
And, Go.
坦纳要十万的聘请定金
Tanner's retainer is $100,000.
这还仅仅只是定金
That's just the retainer.
我有四万七的存款  退休金里还有两千五
Listen, I've got $47,000 in savings. I've got $2,500 in an IRA.
我同意对房子做二次抵押
I'm approved for a second mortgage on the house.
我们可以从这里着手
We will go from there.
谢谢
Thank you.
-我爱你  -我也爱你
- I love you. - I love you, too.
尼克把患有老年痴呆的爸爸送进养老院
Nick keeps his father, who has Alzheimer's, in a facility.
去年他去看望他爸几次呢  就一次
Number of times he visited last year? One.
操
Oh, fuck!
他的双胞胎姐姐  马尔  是个美人
His twin sister, Margo, well, she is a peach.
他俩天天躲在艾米买给他们的酒吧里
These two spend their days in the bar Amy bought them.
玩什么呢  劳伦  玩过家家吗
Playing what, Lauren? Playing house?
他妈的
What the fuck?
双胞胎姐弟经常能激发和教唆对方
Twin siblings often enable and abet.
虽然我没有调查过尼克  或者他姐姐
While I never examined Nick, or his sister,
但他们看起来非常的亲近
they both seem very, very close.
双胞胎乱伦
It's twin-cest.
亲近得让人觉得可疑  劳伦
Disturbingly close, Lauren.
那么  问题就来了
And so, we close with a question.
什么样的道德腐朽
What kind of moral rot,
会让美丽多才  善良聪慧的母亲消失
allows a beautiful, talented, kind, smart, loving mother
而上天却听不到我们愤怒的哭喊
to vanish without the heavens hearing our outraged cries?
能给我支烟吗
Can I bum a cigarette?
艾米·艾略特·邓恩  我们关心你  不会忘记你
Amy Elliott Dunne, we care about you, and we will not forget.
知道还有什么是我们不会忘记的吗
And you know what else we won't forget?
密苏里是有死刑的
Missouri has the death penalty.
阿门
Amen.
我要举报一些可疑的行迹
I'd like to report some strange activity,
就在马尔·邓恩家附近的小木屋间那边
near the woodshed on the property of One Margo Dunne.
怀孕消息传开了吗?
没有就打爆料热线
自杀?
-邓恩先生  -科林斯先生
- Mr. Dunne. - Mr. Collings.
我认得你  在志愿者中心见过
I know you. I saw you at the volunteer center.
我是想帮忙
I wanted to help.
希望你不介意我路过打扰
I hope you don't mind me coming by.
我从你给我妻子写的信上知道了你的地址
I got your address from this letter that you wrote my wife.
我和艾米认为写信这种失落的艺术很美好
Amy and I believe in the lost art of letter-writing.
我一直很好奇  在这么多事之后
I always wondered why you kept in touch after...
为什么还要保持联系
Everything.
在寄宿学校你们交往了两年  对吗
You were together for two years in boarding school, right?
她是我第一任正式的女友
She was my first serious girlfriend.
-为什么分手  -真是个奇怪的问题
- Why did you break up? - That's a strange question.
你对她不好吗  还是背着她有别人了
Did you treat her bad? Did you cheat on her?
这个问题很无礼
That's a rude question.
我告诉你艾米是怎么和我说的吧
Let me tell you what Amy told me.
她甩了你  你完全崩溃了
She dumped you, you completely unraveled.
你跟踪过她  威胁过她
You stalked her, you threatened her.
你曾试图在她床上自杀  被收容治疗
And you attempted suicide in her bed and were institutionalized.
你妻子失踪  你大老远过来就为了说这些吗
Your wife is missing, and you came all this way to tell me this?
我以为会听到这个故事的另一个版本
I thought there might be another side to this story.
科林斯先生
Mr. Collings.
操
Fuck.
艾米·艾略特·邓恩失踪一案
The missing persons case of Amy Elliott Dunne.
她是了不起的艾米儿童读物系列里的
She is the beautiful blonde inspiration
金发美人
for the Amazing Amy kids' book series.
你又在读那本日记
You're reading that diary again?
你知道里面最后写了什么
You know how it ends.
我觉得很有意思
It interests me.
朗达
Hey, Rhonda.
"他会杀了我"  日记最后这么写了
"He's gonna kill me." The end.
他为什么去他爸爸的房子里烧日记本
Why did he go to his dad's house to burn it?
那是私人房产  而且没有人在
It's private. There's no one there.
他为什么没有确保日记被完全烧毁
Why didn't he make sure it actually burned?
因为他触发了警报
Because he tripped the alarm.
你拿着手电筒出现了
You were up his ass with a flashlight.
这整件事透着古怪
The whole thing just feels hinky.
比如发现写着"线索"的信封
Like finding an envelope marked "Clue."
你有听过那句话吗
You ever hear the expression,
"最简单的答案通常是正确的"
"The simplest answer is often the correct one"?
其实  我一直都不觉得那句话是对的
Actually, I've never found that to be true.
-晚安  -晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
七月十日
失踪
五天后
猫王来密苏里州了
Elvis is in Missouri.
谢天谢地  进屋来
Thank God. Come on in.
关于艾米  首先你要知道的是
First thing you have to understand about Amy,
她喜欢教训人
she loves to teach lessons.
-扮演上帝  -对  旧约的神
- Play God. - Yeah, old testament God.
好  继续说
Okay. Keep talking.
她发现我背着她和安迪有了婚外情
She finds out I've been cheating on her with Andie,
决定给我个教训
decides to teach me a lesson.
伪造自己的死亡  并嫁祸给我
Fakes her own death, frames me for it.
房子里的血迹  信用卡  人寿保险
Blood in the house, credit cards, life insurance.
她设置了寻宝游戏
She does the treasure hunt.
现在寻宝游戏成了关键
Now, the treasure hunt is critical.
她把我的婚外情
She's taking us on a tour
展示给大家  还变本加厉
of my infidelities. Rubbing my nose in it.
她把线索一的卡片留给警察
And she leaves clue number one for the police,
引他们去我的办公室
which will lead them back to my office,
而那正是我和安迪经常私会的地方
which is a place where Andie and I would often...
她还在那儿放了一条红色内裤
And she leaves a pair of red panties.
影响你的形象
Right. Racy, looks bad.
-线索二呢  -我爸爸的房子
- Clue two. - My father's house.
另一个我和安迪
Another place where Andie and I
偶尔发生关系的地方
would occasionally have relations.
-线索三呢  -在小木屋
- Clue three? - Woodshed.
-也是我和...-我的天
- Also a location... - Oh, my God.
-我们没处可去  -去开房啊
- We had limited options. - A hotel.
艾米会看见信用卡账单
Amy would have seen the credit card bill.
那就用安迪的信用卡
Put it on Andie's credit card.
安迪的账单会直接传到她爸妈那儿
Andie's statement went right to her parents.
尼克  马尔
Nick, Margo,
我们能谈谈那个棕色房子吗
can we head over to the little brown house?
-它指的是哪儿  -我爸爸家
- This leads us to what? - My dad's house.
爸爸的房子是蓝色的
Dad's house is blue.
爸妈离婚之后  他不在我们身边
After the divorce, when dad wasn't coming around.
我一直都假装他是个间谍  叫布朗先生
I used to pretend that he was a spy named Mr. Brown, who...
为了确保他孩子的安全
For the sake of his children's safety,
不能与他们相认
had to deny their existence.
你从没跟我说过
You never told me that.
你竟然告诉她了
You told her that?
在办公室发现了可以让你定罪的红内裤
We've got incriminating red panties in your office.
你的小木屋里有一堆价值不菲的奢侈品
We've got a showcase showdown worth of crap in your woodshed.
那么  你爸爸的房子里到底有什么
So, what in God's name is at your father's house,
尼克
Nick?
实话实说
And be honest.
我真的不知道
I honestly have no idea.
案发现场 请勿进入
无论他们发现了什么
Whatever they found,
肯定不是什么好东西
I think it's safe to assume that it's very bad.
我们有太多不可控因素
We got a lot of uncontained issues here.
尼克  安迪现在是什么态度
Nick, do you have any idea as to what Andie's mindset is?
守夜之后我们还没联系过
Well, We haven't communicated since the vigil.
好吧  艾米的父母呢
Okay. Amy's parents?
-不好说  -更麻烦了
- No, it's... - More pressure.
我们有个硬伤
We got a hurt,
你的小女朋友随时都可能把事情公之于众
young girlfriend who will no doubt go public at any moment.
-不  安迪不会那么做  -她会的
- No, Andie won't do that. - She will.
这种女孩都会这么做  别感情用事
They always do. Don't take it personally.
艾米巧妙地把我们束缚住了
Amy's got us in an interesting bind.
我们得向警察坦白你和安迪的关系
We need to tell the cops about Andie.
不是吧
Really?
现在安迪的存在让你多了一个杀人动机
Right now, Andie just gives you another motive.
我们还要告诉警察小木屋的事
We need to tell the cops about the woodshed.
我们必须主动坦白
We need to be on the front end of that.
但是我要提醒你接下来会发生的事
But I'm gonna warn you as to what will happen.
他们会逮捕马尔
They'll go after Margo.
他们没权这样做  能吗
They can't do that, can they?
她是你的共犯  帮你隐藏了证据
She's your accomplice. She helped you hide the evidence.
看起来她知道你杀了艾米
In all likelihood, she knows that you killed Amy.
天啊
God.
那我们该怎么做
Well, what are we going to do?
我们得找到艾米
We find Amy.
不  其他策略都忽略了重点
No. Any other strategy is missing the point.
我认识两个前特工哥们  很能干
I've got two ex-secret service guys that are really good.
我叫他们去调查
I'll put them on it.
但是该从哪儿开始找  尼克
But where do they start, Nick?
艾米会去哪儿
Where would Amy go?
不知道
I have no idea.
我们记分吗
Are we keeping score?
喂
Hey!
我还以为我们最近对男性敬而远之呢
I thought we were steering clear of men for a while.
他人很好
He's nice.
因为他想干你
Because he wants to fuck you.
她还在为前任而苦恼吗
She's still moping about her ex?
他也被背叛过
He got cheated on, too.
我们三个是欧扎克最悲伤的人
We three are the saddest sacks in all the Ozarks.
我不悲伤
I'm not sad.
我是生气
I'm angry.
那不就得了
There you go.
我被老婆抛弃那时都要宿醉而死了
I almost drank myself to death when my wife left me.
我想要自杀  你信吗
I was gonna kill myself. Can you believe that?
别便宜了他
Don't give him the pleasure.
我想把自己淹死在墨西哥湾
I was going to drown myself in the Gulf of Mexico.
成为大白鲨的美餐
Let myself be dinner for the great whites.
海湾里都是牛鲨  来自新奥尔良的小姐
Gulf is bull sharks, Miss Nawlins.
为什么要死的是我  我又不是那个混蛋
Why should I die? I'm not the asshole.
应该把这话印在T恤上
Please put that on a t-shirt.
土豪小姐  你不是说你破产了吗
Miss moneybags. I thought you said you were broke.
不少钱啊
That's a fat wad.
都是零头
It's mostly singles.
零头  你做什么的  脱衣舞娘
Singles? What are you, a stripper?
应召女郎  还是"口"艺高超
Swamp girls, or treasure chest?
我们逗你玩呢
We're just teasing.
你们在新奥尔良不开玩笑的吗
Don't they tease people down in nola?
尼克·邓恩随时都可能被捕
We can expect Nick Dunne's arrest any day now.
我们现在发现了房间里的血迹
We've got blood in the house,
巨额债款和意外怀孕
huge debt, an unwanted pregnancy.
而且艾米·艾略特·邓恩已经失踪五天了
And we have Amy Elliott Dunne, missing for five days.
为正义呐喊吧
Crying out for justice.
马上回来
We'll be right back.
七月十一日
失踪
六天后
坦纳想到个坏主意  他要让你露面
Tanner has a very bad idea he's going to pitch you.
是吗
Yeah?
你明天去圣路易斯  上莎伦·希伯的节目
You're doing Sharon Schieber tomorrow in St. Louis.
这么做不合适吧
It could go so wrong.
然后你告诉她安迪的事
And you are going to tell her about Andie.
不
Nope.
这真不是个好主意
That sounds like a very bad idea.
你已经三天没跟她联系了
You haven't heard from her in three days.
这就是个定时炸弹  你会被整得很惨
This is a ticking time bomb. You've gotta throw yourself on it.
人们会恨死我的
People are gonna hate me.
之后他们就会原谅你
And then, they will forgive you.
一个在电视上大方承认自己是混蛋的男人
A guy admitting that he's a gigantic asshole on television?
人们会同情你
People empathize with that.
我们为什么不直接发个声明
Why don't we just put out a statement?
得让他们看见你
They need to see you.
莎伦的节目有上千万的观众
Sharon's specials, they get 10 million viewers.
她很有煽动力  如果她拿你做话题人物
She is a crusader. If she takes you on as a cause...
她会问些犀利的问题
She's going to ask real questions.
我会教你怎么说
I will drill you as if you were doing a deposition.
什么该说  什么不该说
What to say, what not to say.
就像只训练有素的猴子
A trained monkey?
训练有素的猴子不会被处死
A trained monkey who doesn't get the lethal injection.
尼克  这次关乎到人们怎么看你
Nick, this case is about what people think of you.
你得让他们喜欢你
They need to like you.
你这样做会获得成千上万的支持者
Now, you do this and you will reach millions of those people.
也许我只需要得到一个人的支持
Maybe I only need to reach one.
谁啊
Hello?
嗨  亲爱的
Hey, baby.
马上来
One minute.
-嗨  -嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
你要走了吗
You clearing out?
没  我就收拾下房间
No, I'm just cleaning up.
我们进去道别吧
Let us come in and say goodbye.
我等会过去...
I'll come by before...
让我们帮你一把
let us give you a hand.
你收拾得真彻底
Yeah, you gotta clear everything out, here.
桃乐茜真是个细心的人
Dorothy is a real stickler.
连个挂钩都没留下
Not even a spare hanger can you leave behind.
我得确保你没落任何东西
Gotta make sure nothing's tucked inside.
袜子
A sock...
内衣  或者其他什么
or undies or what have you.
你清理得真干净
You did a real good job.
你把钱藏哪了  亲爱的
Where is the money, sweetheart?
看看她裙子底下
Look under her dress.
他让你这么干的吗
He talked you into this?
是我叫他这么干的
I talked him into it.
你们一走我就报警
The second you leave, I'm calling the cops.
你的眼镜是假的  头发也是染的
Your glasses are fake. Your hair's dyed all hamster.
你说你叫南希
You say your name's Nancy,
但喊你名字你总是没反应
but you don't even answer to it half the time.
你在躲避什么
You're hiding.
我不知道为什么  也不关心这个
I don't know why, and I don't really care.
但是你绝对不会报警
But you ain't gonna call the cops.
而且我觉得你也没被虐待过
And I don't think you've ever really been hit before.
我靠
Holy shit.
抱歉  我们真的很需要钱
Sorry, but we really need the money.
下次一定多加小心  明白吗
Next place, be more careful, okay?
外面有很多比我们还坏的人
There are a lot of people out there a lot worse than we are.
抱歉  你不能在这儿睡觉
Excuse me. You can't sleep here.
七月十二日
失踪
七天后
我没有杀害我的妻子
I did not kill my wife.
再来一遍吧  别那么愣
Why don't you try it again? A little less wooden.
我没杀我妻子
I didn't kill my wife.
-干嘛  -你每次表现得自以为是
- What are you doing? - Every time you look smug,
生闷气  或者紧张的时候
or annoyed or tense,
我就拿小熊软糖扔你
I'm gonna hit you with a gummy bear.
难道这能缓解我紧绷的神经吗
That's supposed to make me less tense?
我们再来一遍
Let's try it again.
邓恩先生  据我了解
Mr. Dunne, from what I understand,
你和你的妻子有些矛盾
you and your wife had some bumps.
是  我们这几年过得不是很顺利
Yeah, we had some tough years.
我失业了
I lost my job.
是你们都失业了
You both did.
我们都失业了
We both lost our jobs.
我们不得不回老家照顾我母亲
I had to move back home so we could take care of my mother,
她癌症晚期  我的爸爸...
who was dying of cancer and my dad, who had...
你爸爸提不得
your dad's scorched earth.
尽量谈你的母亲  说说你们的关系
Let's talk about your mom, how close you were.
接着说
Go on.
时间一久  就会积累矛盾
For a while, things had been building up.
"积累"让人感觉要爆发  不能这么说
"Built up" implies that an explosion is coming. No.
可以说  我们的婚姻走上了错误的轨道
At a certain point, we got on the wrong track.
我一时懦弱
I had a moment of weakness.
你的"一时"可是持续了十五个多月
Your "Moment" Was over 15 months.
我对妻子很无礼
I disrespected my wife.
对婚姻不重视
And I disrespected my marriage.
我一直都很后悔
And I'll always regret it.
这话管用
That works.
别怕表现得像个愚蠢的老公  尼克
Don't be afraid to play up the dufus husband thing, Nick.
我就是个傻瓜  我糟透了
I was an idiot. I'm a fuck-up.
我做的一切都是错的
Everything I do is wrong."
我懂男人都需要怎么做
I know. What men are supposed to do in general.
-谢了  -你感觉怎么样
- Thank you. - How do you feel?
感觉不错  能递给我那个盒子吗
I feel good. Go, can you pass me that box, please?
这是艾米在我三十三岁生日时送的礼物
It's Amy's 33rd birthday present to me.
你不喜欢这手表
You hate that watch.
不  我喜欢
No, go. I love that watch.
就像我喜欢这条领带
Just like I love this tie.
就像我爱我的妻子
Just like I love my wife.
赌场
你来了
It's you!
真是你
It's you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
天啊
Good God.
上周
Last week,
我威胁他说我要离开
I threatened to leave,
他说要找到我并且杀了我
and he said he'd find me and he'd kill me.
所以我才消失掉
So, I disappeared.
我流产了
I lost the baby.
我甚至都不敢告诉父母
I couldn't even tell my parents.
我感到很羞耻  也很害怕
I'm so ashamed and I'm so afraid.
他在找你
Well, he is looking for you.
三天前他来过我家
He showed up on my doorstep three days ago.
他看见我给你的信就找过来了
He tracked me from my letters to you.
你还留着那些信
You saved them.
你的存在
Knowing you were out there,
是这几年来唯一支撑我的事
was the only thing that's kept me going these past few years.
我们报警吧  你可以说明一切
Let's go to the police. You can explain everything.
不  我现在不能露面
No, I can't turn up now.
我会很难堪  人人都会瞧不起我
I'd be a pariah. Everyone would hate me.
我想让尼克蹲监狱是不是错了
Is it wrong to want Nick to go to prison?
他应该为他所做的进监狱
He should go to prison for what he's done.
我把你安顿在我的湖边小屋
I'm setting you up at my lake house.
那里非常隐蔽
It's utterly secluded.
你为什么对我这么好
Why are you so good to me?
你知道原因
You know why.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我们见过  对吧
I know you, don't I?
不
No.
你是那个新奥尔良姑娘  对吗
You're one of the Nolan girls, right?
不  我们来自温尼伯  不好意思
No, we're from Winnipeg. Excuse us.
我们该走了
We should leave.
等一下
Just a second.
是邦妮  我待会再给她回电话
That was Boney. I'll call her later.
坦纳  见到你真高兴
Tanner. Nice to see you.
莎伦  你好啊
Sharon! Hi.
希望这次不虚此行
Hope this is worth my while.
你一定会满意的
You're gonna be very happy.
我是莎伦
Sharon.
希伯小姐  非常感谢
Ms. Schieber. Thank you so much for doing this.
采访开始之前你要喝点或吃点什么吗
Can I get you anything to drink or eat before we get started?
不用了  我吃了很多小熊软糖
No, I had some gummy bears.
搞什么
What the fuck?
怎么了
I'm sorry?
我们关于了不起的艾米失踪一案
We have a major shocking development
有了令人震惊的进展
in the amazing Amy disappearance.
现在进行直播
We go live to that story now.
我的天
Oh, my God.
你个小贱货
You little slut.
我叫安迪·菲茨杰拉德
My name is Andie Fitzgerald.
我在学校认识了尼古拉斯·邓恩
I met Nicholas dunne,
他是我的创意写作老师
when he was my creative writing teacher at Mill Valley.
她为什么穿得像个保姆
Why is she dressed like a babysitter?
我非常惭愧
I am deeply ashamed...
与已婚男人发展恋爱关系
of having been romantically involved with a married man.
这个大胸骚货
The girl with the giant cum-on-me tits.
我以为我们是真爱
I truly believed we were in love.
现在开始装圣女了
Now, she looks like a fucking mennonite.
我知道这种事没有借口
I know that is no excuse.
对  没借口
No, it is not.
在我心里
I do not, in my heart,
我不认为尼克·邓恩会为我而杀人
believe Nick Dunne would have killed for me.
我为每个关心艾米的人祈祷
My prayers go out to everyone who loves Amy.
我为给他们带来的伤害而道歉
I apologize for the pain this has caused them.
我们待尼克·邓恩如亲生儿子
We have loved Nick Dunne like a son.
但从今往后 恩断义绝
That love ended today.
走吧  他们看起来很不好
Come on, you're staring at ghosts.
他用无尽的谎言回报我们的信任
He met our trust with lie after lie.
我们现在坚定地相信
We now absolutely believe,
尼克与我们女儿的失踪有很大关系
Nick is involved in the disappearance of our daughter.
我们的了不起的艾米
Our amazing Amy.
真是个劲爆的消息
Well, this just got very exciting.
我们需要点时间
We need a moment.
我们得取消访谈
We're gonna have to bow out of this.
-什么都没变  -一切都变了
- Nothing has changed. - Everything has changed.
一小时之间
An hour ago,
我们还掌握主动权  现在呢
we were ahead of this. Now?
-我能处理好  -我们是被动的
- I can handle this. - We're on the defense.
现在的事态完全不同了
This is a completely different dynamic.
-我能处理好  -她能活剥了你
- I can handle it. - She's going to eat you alive.
相信我
Just trust me.
来吧
Okay.
很好
Great.
把麦克风给他
Mic him.
一  二  三  四  五
One, two, three, four, five.
谢谢
Thank you.
他不该对化妆师微笑
He shouldn't smile at the makeup artist.
就是  呵呵
Yeah, no kidding.
准备  五  四
Roll tape. Five, four,
三  二
three, two...
说真的  我都不敢相信你表现得这么好
Seriously, I can't believe how fucking good you were.
是艾米激发出了我的潜能
Amy brings out the best in me.
别这么说
Don't.
你们两个别放松
Keep it together, you two.
至少在接下来的二十四小时里
At least for the next 24 hours.
大家仍然不喜欢你
People still hate you.
女人都恨不得把你眼珠子挖出来
Women want to scratch your eyes out.
安迪在电视上的表现很奏效
Andie was really good TV.
-她是公众心里的好人  -这就是问题
- She's a good person. - There is lies the problem.
我们得平息这场风波
Ride this out,
明天莎伦的节目一播出
and when Sharon airs tomorrow,
我们将会看见一个崭新的你
we'll be looking at a whole new you.
但在那之前
But, until then...
别露面
Don't show your face.
没问题
No problem.
欢迎
Welcome.
别拘束
Make yourself at home.
这里有音乐  有线电视
I've got music, satellite...
在线电影
Netflix.
他是她的老师
He was her teacher!
数字电视
Roku.
当然还有网络
Internet, obviously.
一个成年男子
Here is a supposedly grown man...
如果你想吃什么
If there is ever anything
但是找不到的话
you have a taste for and you can't find it.
告诉我  我给你买
Just let me know and I will get it for you.
除了专业课  他还给她上了一堂性教育课
Instead of the a-b-c's, he taught her the birds and the bees.
她妈妈这个时候又会怎么想呢
And just think how her mother must feel at a time like this.
楼下有藏酒室
Wine cellar's downstairs.
我还会给你买些衣服
I'll get you some clothes, too.
不是说你这身不好看
Not that I don't appreciate bait shop chic.
地板是暖的  按你喜好调的温度
The floors are heated, just dial to your liking.
这里有浴袍和毛巾  浴室里有桑拿
There's robes and towels. The shower has steam.
浴缸是按摩式的
The bathtub has a massage cycle.
如果你心情好  可以看看窗外的美景
There's a great view, if you're in the mood.
心情不好就拉上窗帘
Blackout curtains if you're not.
床垫是萨维的
The bed is savoir.
英国奢华床具品牌
你一定会睡得很好
You'll never get a better sleep.
我正需要好好睡一觉
This is just what I need.
我很累了
I'm so exhausted.
那我就让你好好休息吧
I'll leave you to it, then.
艾米  我很高兴你在这里
Amy, I am so happy that you are here.
我不希望你有丝毫担忧
And I don't want you to worry for one moment.
这里到处都是摄像头
There are cameras everywhere.
房子内外所有入口角落都有
The exterior, all along the grounds, the entryway.
任何人
Anyone,
进来或出去
who is caught coming or going,
都会被拍下来
will be recorded.
你很安全
You are more than safe.
我不会再让你跑掉了
And I am not letting you get away again.
七月十三日
失踪
八天后
-早上好  -别这样
- Good morning! - Don't do that!
对不起
I'm sorry.
我需要有安全感
I need to feel safe.
你很安全
You are very safe.
-你想干什么  -没干什么
- What have you been up to? - Nothing.
艾米  我不是尼克
Amy, I'm not Nick.
这对我来说很困难
It's hard for me.
这么多年来  一直被人操纵着
After so many years under someone's thumb...
我懂你的感受
I know just what that feels like.
我从来没有操纵过你
You were never under my thumb.
-被你牵着鼻子走  -从未有过
- On your leash. - Never.
一个新的开始
A new start.
得体的衣服
Decent clothes.
染发剂  化妆品  眉钳
Hair dye. Makeup. Tweezers.
那边的健身房可以俯瞰整个湖
There's a gym overlooking the lake.
你越快看起来像自己
The sooner you look like yourself,
你就会感到越自在
the sooner you'll feel like yourself.
我出去为今晚买点东西
I'll get groceries for tonight,
我们今晚看莎伦·希伯的秀  做个了结
we'll watch Sharon Schieber, and finally move on.
我觉得我应该自己一个人看
I think that's something I should watch on my own.
胡说
Nonsense.
我会回来的
I'll be back.
我期待着
And I am looking forward
跟艾米·艾略特的重聚
to my reunion with Amy Elliott.
这下可好了
Great.
晚上好  我是莎伦·希伯
Good evening, I'm Sharon Schieber.
-今晚  终于  -赶紧
- Tonight, exclusively. - Hurry up.
一位丈夫要打破沉默
A husband breaks his silence,
不仅向我们披露他妻子失踪的内幕
not just on his wife's disappearance.
还回应了他的外遇和外界传言
But on his infidelity, and all those shocking rumors.
尼克·邓恩
Nick Dunne.
你现在估计是全美最被讨厌的男人了
You're probably the most hated man in America right now.
是的  而且是我自己活该
I probably am. And I probably deserve it.
那条领带是我买的
I bought that tie.
你杀了你妻子吗  尼克
Did you kill your wife, Nick?
我没有杀我妻子
I did not kill my wife.
我不是杀人犯
I am not a murderer.
但是你出轨了
But you were unfaithful.
我是出轨了
I was unfaithful.
我也感到很羞愧
And I am deeply ashamed.
更严重的是  你让艾米的父母
And, on top of that, you allowed Amy's parents,
她的朋友  以及你镇上的所有人
her friends, all the people in your hometown,
相信你是个忠诚的丈夫
Believe you were a loving husband,
急切地寻找自己失踪的妻子
desperate to find his missing wife.
我的确很急切要找到我的妻子
Well, I am desperate to find my missing wife.
说是这么说  不过我很好奇
You say that, but I'm wondering,
你要怎么让我们相信你
how you expect us to believe you.
我们现在知道你是个骗子
Now that we know you're a liar.
我之前没承认自己有外遇
I didn't come forward with my affair.
因为我知道  这会让我看起来坏得无可救药
Because I knew it would make me look really, really bad.
但我已经不在乎了
But I don't care about that anymore.
我只是想找到我的妻子
I just want to find my wife.
-我只是想搞清楚  -让我给你说清楚
- I'm just trying to get clear... - let me be clear.
我虽然不是个杀人犯  我也不是个好人
Just because I am not a murderer doesn't make me a good guy.
我不是个好人
I'm not a good guy.
我是一位好妻子的坏丈夫
I was a bad husband to a great wife.
我打破了对她的誓言
I broke the vow that I made to her.
说得真好  尼克
Those are pretty words, Nick.
但这对你来说到底意味着什么
But what does that really mean to you?
我是个彻头彻尾的骗子
It basically means that I was a con artist.
七年前  我遇到艾米·艾略特
I met Amy Elliott seven years ago.
我完全被迷住了
I was completely transfixed.
艾米非常迷人
Amy can do that to you.
我只是一个普通的男人
I was this average guy from an average place.
怀揣着一丝梦想
with mediocre aspirations.
我遇到了一个让我为之倾倒的女人
And I met a woman who dazzled me.
我希望得到她的爱
And I wanted her to love me.
所以我假装自己很优秀
So I pretended to be better than I was.
在我们结婚时  我承诺会成为那样的人
When we got married, I promised to be that guy.
一个勤奋工作的人
That guy who works harder.
一个跟她一样  努力向上
That guy who, who lives and acts,
用尽全力去爱的人
and loves with as much passion as she does.
但我让她失望了
But I failed her.
我没有正确处理事情
Instead of doing what was right.
我选择了逃避
I did what was easy.
你说得好像你的妻子能起死回生
You talk like a man who believes he can make amends to his wife.
还活着似的
Who believes his wife is still alive.
她的确还活着
She is still alive.
你能看着镜头吗
Will you look at that camera for me?
看着镜头
Will you look in the lens,
跟你的妻子说话
and talk to your wife?
如果她依然活着  能看到你今晚的采访
If she is out there, able to hear and see you tonight.
你会对她说什么  尼克
What would you like to say to her, Nick?
艾米  我爱你
Amy, I love you.
你是我见过最棒的人
You're the best person I've ever known.
我已经对我的所作所为
And I've taken myself to the
感到无比后悔
woodshed for the way that I've treated you.
如果你能回来  我保证
And if you come back, I promise,
我会花一辈子的时间去弥补你
I will spend every day making it up to you.
我会成为我承诺的完美男人
I will be the man that I promised you I would be.
我爱你
I love you.
回家吧
Come home.
给我
Here.
不管你怎么想
Regardless of what you thought,
怎么样
What does it say?
我想我们都同意
I think we can all agree,
天啊  你太厉害了
Oh, my God. You fucking killed it.
事情远远没那么简单
there's more to him than meets the eye.
他们都为你疯狂
They're going crazy for you.
他们从不喜欢我  喜欢我  恨我
They disliked me, they liked me, they hated me,
变成了爱我
and now they love me.
坦诚的人值得尊重
A candor and an honesty that's worthy of respect.
很显然  他赢得了我的尊重
He's certainly earned mine.
怎么了
What is it?
我是莎伦·希伯  晚安
I'm Sharon Schieber. Good night.
马尔·邓恩  这是搜查令
Margo Dunne, this is a search warrant for your property.
我通常会忽略爆料电话
I usually ignore tipline calls.
但有邻居看到陌生男子
But a neighbor was concerned
在你的小木屋附近游荡
about a strange man around your woodshed.
打给坦纳
Call Tanner.
该死的
Okay. Fuck!
你的女朋友很可爱  尼克
Girlfriend's real cute, Nick.
是因为这件事吗
Is that what this is about?
整个调查中
I have treated you more than fair
我都对你很公平
throughout this entire investigation.
我一次又一次给你机会坦白
I gave you the benefit of the doubt over and over.
每次你说了愚蠢的话
Every time you said something stupid.
我就想  他只是蠢而已
I thought, "Maybe he's just stupid."
但我错了  事情原来是这样的
But I was wrong. That's what this is about.
这些就是你不用的高尔夫球杆吗
Are these the clubs you don't play golf with?
那些全都不是我的
None of that is mine.
也不是我放在这里的
None of this was put here by me.
很不错的球杆
Those are nice clubs.
好一个男人的密室
You got the makings of a real man cave.
就等着妻子永远消失了
Everything just waiting until the wife goes away for good.
尼克
Nick!
-你们不能这样做  -我们当然可以
- You can't do that! - Of course we can.
艾米  是时候重新开始了
Amy, it's time to move on.
我有什么能帮忙的吗
What can I do to help?
我需要时间考虑
I need some time to think.
-这是你最不需要的  -德西
- That's the last thing you need. - Desi.
二十年来  你一直让我等
Twenty years, you have kept me dangling.
你昨晚终于来见我了  你选择了我
Finally, last night, you came to me, and you chose me.
跟着昨晚的直觉走
Follow that instinct.
不要再让自己挨打
Don't trust the instinct that left you beaten,
睡在车里无家可归  担惊受怕
and homeless, sleeping in your car, fearing for your life.
我不会强迫你
I'm not gonna force myself on you.
你说的我都懂  德西
I understand what you're saying, Desi.
我真的懂
I do.
我被长时间虐待
Just been... I've been so mistreated for so long.
都忘了如何处事
I've forgotten how to behave.
我明天会搬进来
I'll move in here tomorrow.
我们一起想办法解决
And we'll work it out together.
我只想要你做回自己
I just want you to be you again.
他们抓走马尔是为了吓唬你
They only took Margo to fuck with you.
我不能让她在那里多待一秒
She's not spending another fucking second in there.
我要进去告诉他们真相
I'm gonna go in, and I'm gonna tell them everything.
怎么了
What?
我们只能跟邦妮透漏一点
We tell Boney very little.
没有尸体  没有凶器
Without a body, without a murder weapon.
他们只能期望你认罪
Their only hope is a confession.
把说话权让给他们
So, you let them do all the talking.
那我们就有时间组织你的辩词
That way, we can jump-start your defense.
真相就是我的辩词
The truth is my defense.
认得它们吗
Recognize these?
艾米送我的周年纪念日礼物
Yes. It's Amy's anniversary present to me.
她是通过这些告诉你她怀孕的吗  尼克
Was that how she told you she was pregnant, Nick?
妈妈爸爸孩子  这就让你生气了吗
Mommy, daddy, baby, and that made you real mad?
不
No.
-认得这个吗  -从未见过
- Recognize this? - Never seen that before in my life.
这是艾米的日记  在你爸爸家里找到的
It's Amy's diary. We found this at your father's house.
这是你妻子的笔迹吗
Is this your wife's handwriting?
-他又不是鉴定专...  -看上去是
- He's not a handwriting ex... - looks like it.
我们的专家也这样认为
Our experts thought so, too.
我们来玩个是真还是假的游戏
Do you wanna play a little true or false?
没问题
Sure.
"他抹掉我嘴唇上的糖霜  吻了我"
"And then he brushes the sugar off my lips so he can taste me."
真的
Yeah, that's true.
你还以为藜麦是种鱼
You thought quinoa was a fish?
这也是真的
That is also true, yes.
她想要孩子  你攻击了她
She wanted to get pregnant, you assaulted her.
我打了她  从来没有
I hit her? No, never happened.
-这里说的是推  -完全没有
- "Pushed," It says "Pushed." - Absolutely not.
我从来没碰过她
I never touched her.
她试图去买枪
She tried to buy a gun.
不会吧  不过我也不知道
I doubt that, but I don't know.
我要读下最后一句吗
Shall I read the last entry?
读吧
Sure.
"这男人可能会杀了我"
"This man may kill me."
她的原话  "这男人可能会杀了我"
In her own words, "This man may kill me."
就是个简单的尾注罢了
It's kind of a convenient end note.
以备日后参考
For future reference.
记住  你不是笔迹鉴定专家
The truth, you are not a handwriting expert.
我知道了
Okay, I know.
朱蒂失踪的手柄
Judy's missing handle.
宽四寸厚二尺  跟球杆一样大
Big as a two-by-four, right? Big as a club.
我们第一天在你家办公室的壁炉里找到的
We found this day one, in the fireplace in your home office.
我们一开始不知道是什么
We didn't know what the hell it was,
但七月里生火吗
but fire in July?
我们把它包了起来
We bagged it.
我也从未见过
I've never seen that before either.
我们验过了  火是抹不去血迹的  尼克
We just tested it. Fire doesn't erase blood, Nick.
尼古拉斯·邓恩
So, finally, Nicholas Dunne,
你因杀害你妻子而被捕
you're under arrest for the murder of your wife.
别说话
Do not say another word.
-不听听我的辩词吗  -尼克
- What about my side? - Nick!
七月二十六日
失踪
二十一天后
还要咖啡吗
More coffee?
好的
I'd love it.
记得以前我们逃课去的那个岬角吗
Remember that time we skipped school and drove to the cape?
当然  现捞的龙虾
God, yeah. Lobster right from the ocean.
真让我怀念以前
This reminds me of that.
过不完的假期
Never-ending holiday.
你不无聊吗
You're not bored?
德西  我怎么会无聊呢
Desi, how could I be bored?
你可以谈论十八世纪的交响乐
You can discuss 18th-century symphonies.
十九世纪的印象派
19th-century impressionists,
引用普鲁斯特的原文
quote Proust in French.
法国小说家
尼克对文化的了解
Nick's idea of culture was
只限于边看电视剧
a reality TV marathon
边打飞机
with one hand down his boxers.
我得走了
I really have to get going.
我会尽快回来的
But I will be back just as soon as I can.
我的钥匙
My keys.
谢谢
Thank you.
年轻人都这样穿
That's how the kids wear it.
邓恩  有律师要见你
Dunne? You got one hell of a lawyer.
-你还好吗  -还好  你呢
- Are you okay? - Yes. Are you?
走吧
Let's go.
现在怎么样了
So... what does this mean?
你可以出狱了
Well, you're out on bond.
舒舒服服在家准备庭审
You can relax at home while we prep for trial.
低着头
Keep your head down.
坦纳  有任何艾米的消息吗
Tanner, is there any fucking lead on Amy?
我的两个得力助手在查
I've got two of my best guys on it.
她就像消失在空气了
She's air.
有种你就回家  艾米
Come home, Amy. I dare you.
八月三日
失踪
二十九天后
科林斯先生到家咯
Mr. Collings is home.
你好  科林斯先生
Hello, Mr. Collings.
我想你了
I've missed you.
我一直在想
I've been thinking...
我不能离开你
I don't wanna be without you.
留下来陪我
Stay with me.
这一切结束后
And when all this dies down,
按你说的  我们去希腊
we'll go to Greece, like you said.
章鱼和拼字游戏吗
Octopus and scrabble?
你觉得离结束还有多久呢
How long do you think until it's done?
不久了  六个月的庭审
Not long. Six months for the trials.
判决很快的
Sentencing will be quick.
他会上诉的
He'll appeal.
其他的我可以在国外看
I can watch the rest overseas.
慢点来
Go slowly.
我就想要
But I want it.
别急
Don't rush.
上我吧
Just do it.
再快点
Harder.
八月四日
失踪
三十天后
你个婊子
You fucking bitch.
别担心  你们还会有很多小孩的
Don't you worry, you're gonna have lots of babies.
她的伤口是被强奸导致的  有精液残留
Her wounds are consistent with rape. There was semen present.
我们会确保找到匹配者
We'll make sure it's a match.
会找到的
Yeah, it'll match.
非常感谢你
Thank you very much.
你怎么看
What do you think?
咱俩又成好友啦
Are we pals again?
我知道你没杀你的妻子  所以是的
Now that I know you didn't murder your wife, yes.
你怎么看
What do you think?
绑架  这故事太扯了
Kidnapping? The story's insane.
她吃了好多止痛药
She's on fairly heavy painkillers.
没关系  我想帮忙
It's okay. I want to help.
邓恩女士  我知道你受了不少苦
Ms. Dunne, I know what you've been through
所以我们会尽量简短
so we'll keep this very brief.
你能给我们讲一下事发经过吗
Can you walk us through what happened?
那天早晨我听到门铃响
That morning, the doorbell rang.
很正常
So normal.
于是我打开了门
I opened the door.
好奇怪
So strange.
从高中起  他就不肯放过我
Since high school, he won't ever go away.
而我只是不想伤害他
And I've just tried to be nice to him.
于是我给他回信
Answer his letters.
让他保持冷静
Keep him calm.
天啊
Oh, my God.
是我鼓励了他的行为
I've encouraged him.
你不能怪自己
You can't blame yourself.
他推开门进了屋
He pushed inside.
然后就抓住我
And he grabbed me.
但我挣脱了  跑到了厨房
But I got away, and ran to the kitchen.
他用棒子打我
And he clubbed me.
我跌倒了
I collapsed.
那根棍子实际上是一个潘趣和朱迪玩偶的手柄
That club was actually the handle to a Punch and Judy puppet.
没错
Right.
寻宝游戏
Treasure hunt.
我在马尔家藏了一些玩偶
I'd hidden some puppets at Go's...
那这个手柄怎么会落在德西手里呢
Then how did Desi have that handle?
是我随手抓到的
I'd just found it.
它肯定是掉下来了
It must have fallen off.
德西推门闯进来时我正抓着它
I was holding it when Desi pushed in.
所以他是从我那抢的
So, he got it from me.
关于那个小木屋...
About that woodshed...
他把我带到他的湖边小屋
He took me to his lake house.
把我绑到他的床上
Tied me to his bed.
再说一下那个小木屋  很快  很快
Back to the woodshed real quick. Real quick.
你去那里放玩偶的时候
When you went to place the puppets there,
有没有注意到那个棚屋很满
did you notice that it was packed...
里面好多东西
Lots of stuff.
都是用你丈夫名下的信用卡
Corresponding to purchases
买来的东西
made on credit cards in your husband's name.
尼克和他的信用卡
Nick and credit cards.
他买东西  我唠叨  我不知道  也许吧
He buys, I nag. I don't know, probably.
他在马尔家藏了很多东西
He hid a lot of stuff at Go's.
他们俩很亲近
They're very close.
我现在可以继续讲我被一个
Now, may I go back to where I was being held prisoner
有精神病史的人囚禁的事了吗
by a man with a history of mental problems?
请继续  邓恩女士
Please continue, Ms. Dunne.
德西当晚侵犯了我
Desi assaulted me that night.
晚晚如此
Every night.
他把我像狗一样绑着
He tied me up like a dog.
然后他就惩罚我
And then, he'd punish me.
饿着我
Starve me.
给我除毛
Shave me.
鸡奸我
Sodomize me.
他家到处都是摄像头
There were cameras everywhere.
请找出来  请把录像带找出来
Please find this. Please find the tapes.
她用开箱刀割了他的喉咙
She slit his throat with a box cutter.
如果她一直被他绑着
How did she manage to get a hold of a box cutter,
那她是怎么拿到开箱刀的呢
if he had her tied up the whole time?
你就不能为你妻子安全回家而开心吗
Can't you just be happy your wife is home and safe?
艾米  我们找到了你的日记
Amy, we found your diary.
里面你多次指控
It contains many concerning
你丈夫对你进行精神和身体上的虐待
allegations of mental and physical abuse.
这就是丑恶的真相
Well, it's the ugly truth.
尼克不想要孩子
Nick didn't want a baby.
他脾气大  我们还有经济问题
He has a temper. We had money problems.
但我爱他
But I love him.
那你为什么要买枪呢
Then why did you try to buy a gun?
对不起  我觉得我要晕了
I'm sorry, I feel myself fading.
请再让我问清楚一件事
If I could just clarify one thing...
如果这个案子一直交给你这么无能的人
If this case had been left in your deeply incompetent hands
我丈夫肯定早就被判了死刑
my husband would be on death row,
而我肯定还被绑在床上呢
and I'd be tied, still, spread-eagle.
邓恩女士  您很勇敢  我们问完了
Ms. Dunne, you've been very brave. We're finished.
现在  我得问你
Now, I have to ask you
你觉得和你丈夫回家安全吗
do you feel safe going home with your husband?
我们向上帝祈祷  上帝回应了我们的祷告
We prayed to God, and God has answered our prayers.
艾米·邓恩回家了
Amy Dunne is home.
我知道你们有很多问题和担忧
Now, I know there are a lot of questions and concerns
但现在  我们要耐心等待
but for right now, we wanna sit tight,
心怀感激
and just be thankful
感激降临在密西西比的这一奇迹
and grateful for this miracle on the Mississippi.
让一让  借过一下
Excuse me. Excuse us, folks.
我们爱你  艾米
We love you, Amy!
好了  你可以不用再装了
All right, you can stop pretending now.
我没装啊
I'm not pretending.
你很完美
You were perfect.
电视上的尼克正是我当初爱上的那人
The Nick I saw on TV, that's the Nick I fell in love with.
你知道我只是
You do know I was just
故意拣你想听的说  对吧
telling you what you wanted to hear, right?
这证明你有多了解我
That's how well you know me.
你对我的了解深入骨髓
You know me in your marrow.
好吧
Okay.
你得告诉我到底发生了什么
You need to tell me exactly what happened.
把衣服脱了
Take off your clothes.
我得确定你没带窃听器
I need to make sure you're not wearing a wire.
你杀了人  艾米  你是个杀人犯
You killed someone, Amy. You're a murderer.
我是个斗士
I'm a fighter.
我冲破荆棘回到你身边
I fought my way back to you.
你杀了个人
You killed a guy.
你用开箱刀割破了他的喉咙
You slashed his throat with a box cutter.
你上了国家电视台
You went on national television
求我救你一命
and begged for me to save your life.
于是我就救了你
And I obliged.
但我要那个尼克
But I want that Nick.
我要走了
I'm leaving.
你真的认为这样做明智吗
You really think that's smart?
洗发水
Shampoo.
身受重伤惨遭强奸的妻子奋力回到丈夫身边
Wounded, raped wife battles her way back to her husband,
却遭丈夫狠心抛弃
and he deserts her.
他们会毁了你的
They'll destroy you.
邻居们也会避开你
Neighbors will shun you.
而我会确保所有人都记得你带给我的伤痛
And I'll make sure that no one forgets the pain you caused me.
我不想跟门口你那些粉丝有任何瓜葛
I don't want anything to do with your groupies outside.
他们一走
Once they go,
我就走
I go.
你今晚好好再考虑一下
Give it the night. Sleep on it.
你真的怀过孕吗
Was there ever a baby?
你想要的话
There can be.
晚安
Good night.
尼克
Hey, Nick!
八月五日
回家
一日后
早上好  帅哥
Hello, handsome.
要可丽饼吗
Crepe?
好
Sure.
她是他的梦中情人
She was his dream girl.
当这个拥有巨额遗产
And when this spoiled, rich,
被宠坏的富家子发现自己无法得到她
entitled little boy couldn't have her
就把她掳走了
he took her.
你们肯定超自豪
You must be so proud.
已经四个小时了
It's been four hours.
尼克  尼克  你和艾米下一步有何打算
Nick? Nick? What's next for you and Amy?
现在最重要的是我们的婚姻
Right now, it's all about our marriage.
两个人彼此相爱  却没法经营婚姻
When two people love each other and can't make that work
这才是真正的悲剧
that's the real tragedy.
吻我的脸
Kiss my cheek.
不敢相信那该死的蛇蝎女人居然成了美国甜心
I can't believe that fucking spider is America's sweetheart.
八月九日
回家
五日后
第二次相爱的机会
她亲口跟我说她杀了德西
She told me she killed Desi.
不是自卫  而是谋杀
Not self-defense. Murder.
-我们就不能弄个窃听器吗  -没用的
- Can't we get a wire? - That's not gonna work.
她之前都跟你说过一次了
She told you once before.
但她逼我脱光衣服站在花洒下
Yeah, because she had me strip naked, and stand in the shower.
我发誓  你俩是我见过最狗血的人了
I swear, you two are the most fucked-up people I've ever known.
而我还专攻狗血案
And I specialize in fucked-up.
你和艾米住在同一个屋檐下
You and Amy under the same roof?
真该把这个拍成真人秀
You should pitch that as reality television.
艾米·邓恩  密西西比的奇迹
Amy Dunne, and the miracle on the Mississippi.
我和尼克经历了一段困难时期
Nick and I have been through some bad patches.
我们也有不顺的时候
We've had our dark days.
但我们非常感谢大家
But we thank you so much,
原谅尼克  支持我们共建新生活
for supporting us in our new life together, for forgiving Nick.
真的  你们的鼓励对我们意义重大
Really, your encouragement means the world.
她真厉害
She's good.
了不起的艾米和低声下气的丈夫
Amazing Amy and the humbled husband.
密苏里州版的《比弗利娇妻》
The Real Housewives of Branson.
照顾好这家伙
Take care of this guy, will you?
你居然就这么走了
I can't believe you're just leaving now.
你现在不再身处险境了
You are not at risk anymore.
我全身都写满了"身处险境"
I'm the definition of "at risk".
有人请你写书  拍电影
You got a book deal, a lifetime movie,
酒吧也变成了连锁
you franchised the bar.
你也许该感谢她
You may wanna thank her.
就是千万别惹急她
Just don't piss her off.
再见了
See you, guys.
猫王离开密苏里州了
Elvis has left Missouri.
她在杀人过程中肯定犯了错
She had to have made a mistake.
我们得逐句核实艾米的故事
We need to check Amy's story, piece by piece.
尼克  我什么都做不了
Nick, I can't do anything.
全国的焦点都在我们身上  但我们搞砸了
We had the national spotlight on us, we stained the rug.
这案子现在归联调局管  警局已经不插手了
The case is with the feds now, they're done.
可这不意味着你也得撒手不管啊
That doesn't mean you have to be done.
我管不了
It does.
九月九日
回家
五周后
你在干吗
What are you doing?
我睡不着
Couldn't sleep.
来吧
Come on
我陪你回去睡
let me tuck you back in.
你知道你可以跟我一起睡对吧
You know you can sleep with me, right?
知道  只不过
Yeah, it's just
我还需要点时间
I need more time.
我永远永远都不会伤害你的
I would never, ever hurt you.
但我确实需要你的参与
I do need you to participate, though.
我需要你演好自己的角色
I need you to do your part.
好了
Okay.
九月二十三日
回家
七周后
你们听到的关于我妻子的一切
Everything you have heard about my wife
都是谎言
is a lie.
她是个工于心计  凶残的变态
She is a calculating, murderous psychopath.
我一直和她串通一气
And I have been complicit...
尼克
Nick!
尼克  早餐好了
Nick? Breakfast.
亲爱的
Honey?
我们该拉手
We should hold hands.
不用一直拉着  但要偶尔拉一下
Not the entire time, but on and off throughout.
"尼克  娇妻失而复得感觉如何"
"So, Nick, how does it feel to have your wife back?"
感觉棒极了
"It's fantastic.
多少人能如此幸运
How many people are lucky
有机会再次获得爱
enough to get a second chance at love?"
"棒极了"有点轻浮
"Fantastic" is a little flippant.
"了不起"
"Amazing"?
我要你承认你用信用卡买了那些东西
I need you to admit that you got the credit cards,
并藏在了马尔家  还有你推了我
and that you hid all that stuff at Go's and that you pushed me.
我需要那三样东西来获得安全感
I'm gonna need those three things to feel safe.
你必须说得跟真的一样  尼克
You have to own this, Nick.
别担心  我知道该怎么说
Don't worry. I know exactly what to say.
尼克
Nick.
你家真漂亮
What a beautiful home.
我很感谢你为我们抽出时间  尼克
I so appreciate you giving us this time, Nick.
你在国家电视台上
You went on national television,
跟大众说我谋杀了我的妻子
and told people that I murdered my wife.
我是跟着故事走
I go where the story goes.
你暗示我跟我姐之间存在不伦关系
You implied that I had carnal relations with my sister.
我可没那么说  只是说你们俩"非常亲近"
I didn't use the "I" word. I said you two were "Extremely close."
你和一群笨蛋把我分析成反社会者
You and a panel of nitwits diagnosed me as a sociopath.
为打破僵局  我带了这个
Ice-breaker.
正好配你的机器狗
To go with your robot dog.
我去叫艾米
I'll go find Amy.
她在楼下了
She's downstairs.
-这是什么  -送你的
- What is it? - It's for you.
打开看看
Open it.
你不用再送礼物给我了
I don't need any more gifts from you.
打开看看
Open it.
我根本没碰过你
I didn't touch you.
你不需要碰我
You didn't need to.
胡扯  那张废弃通知书
Bullshit. That notice of disposal.
我有的  被你给扔了
I have that. You threw it out.
那张通知书  没错
The notice, yes.
我要验血
I want a blood test.
我要做亲子鉴定
I want a paternity test.
我最爱做鉴定了
I love tests.
随便你怎么教那些人恨我
You can teach those people to hate me all you want.
我不在乎  我要离开你
I don't care. I am leaving you.
我不用教你的孩子恨你
I won't have to teach your child to hate you.
他自己就会了
He'll do that all by himself.
你这个该死的婊子
You fucking cunt!
那我也是你娶回家的婊子
I'm the cunt you married.
你唯一喜欢自己的时候
The only time you liked yourself,
就是当你努力成为这个婊子喜欢的人的时候
was when you were trying to be someone this cunt might like.
我不会放弃的  我就是这种婊子
I'm not a quitter. I'm that cunt.
我为你杀过人  还有谁能这么说
I've killed for you. Who else can say that?
你以为你娶个中西部的小姑娘就开心了
You think you would be happy with a nice midwestern girl?
不可能的  宝贝  你要的人就是我
No way, baby. I'm it.
你有妄想症  你神经错乱了
Look, you're delusional. You're insane.
你做这些到底是为什么呀
Why would you even want this?
是  我是爱过你
Yes, I loved you.
可后来咱俩只剩互相怨恨
And then all we did was resent each other,
互相试图控制对方
and try to control each other.
和给对方造成痛苦了
And cause each other pain.
这就是婚姻
That's marriage.
我要去准备了
Now, I'm getting ready.
我无法眼睁睁地看着你
I can't watch you
在接下来的十八年里跟那破鞋玩过家家
play house with that thing for the next 18 years.
我不能一走了之
I can't just walk away.
你可以获得监护权
You could get custody.
不可能的  你也清楚
No, I won't. And you know it.
那将是我的孩子  我不会丢下他的
It's gonna be my child. I'm not gonna leave it.
你想留下来
You wanna stay.
我有责任  这不再是我想不想的问题了
I have a responsibility. It's not about what I want anymore.
你想跟她在一起
You wanna stay with her.
我的心都被你伤透了
You're breaking my heart.
马尔  你是我的理性之声
Go, you're my voice of reason.
我需要你在我的身边
I need you with me on this.
我当然会在你身边
Of course I'm with you.
咱俩还没出生  我就在你身边了
I was with you before we were even born.
我们经历过黑暗时期
We've been through the darkness.
我们走了出来  更加亲密
We've come out, united.
我们会沟通
We communicate.
我们对彼此诚实
We're honest with each other.
对吧
Right?
我们是犯罪团伙
We're partners in crime.
还有呢
And?
还有
我们要当父母了
We're gonna be parents.
天啊
My goodness!
-太激动人心了  -谢谢
- How exciting! - Thank you.
"你在想什么"
"What are you thinking?"
"你感觉怎么样"
"How are you feeling?"
"我们对彼此做了些什么"
"What have we done to each other?"
"我们将何去何从"
"What will we do?"